Chapter 4: Zimbardo's Methodology Was Flawed, Pt 3

Here's how it is:

Shortly after the story in HPMOR, Hermione decides it is up to her to destroy Azkaban's dementors, even knowing the risks involved. A phoenix arrives to assist her, but after teleporting away with Hermione, immediately returns to Hogwarts. Hermione is left alone in dementor-central while Harry desperately tries to get the phoenix to her before it's too late.

Draco is angry at the world; at the perceived failures and betrayals of everyone around him. In a flash of incite, Draco concludes that Harry is Voldemort and is the biggest threat to magical society. He begins planning to amass power for the inevitable battle.

"So you can't teleport directly to Azkaban and can't fly to it. The obvious solution is to teleport above the wards and fall right where you want to go. Unfortunately, I don't know exactly how high or wide the wards extend. But if you start at an altitude of 100km, several kilometers east of the prison, you'll almost certainly be outside the wards, and the earth's rotation will bring Azkaban to you. I'm not sure how resistant you are to the low temperatures and pressures in the upper atmosphere, and don't want you to have to regenerate after you land, so I'm going to transfigure a capsule for you. That will also have the advantage of having a more easily estimated coefficient of drag and terminal velocity. I'll put some fins and a parachute on the capsule so you can steer toward the prison once you see it and then land safely... Sometime soon, I'm going to either need a working computer in here or a magical way to solve equations..."

A deafening shriek filled the prison, accompanied by a noticeable tremor. An auror was coming down the spiral, now two floors above Hermione, and she could clearly hear a voice yell from his communication mirror, "does anyone know what the hell that was?"

The response also came from the mirror, "Something tore through the outer wall of the prison, sir. It's ... hold on a second ... Be careful, everyone. We must have a seriously powerful dark wizard in the prison."

"Report. What's going on up there, Nobbs?"

"A phoenix came for me, to help me defeat the dark wizard. Does anyone know if they normally arrive in some kind of big metal egg-thing?"

"What?"

"Huh. It keeps falling over." He pauses, laughing. "It looks dizzy. And confused. If I didn't know any better, I'd say it has a concussion."

Hermione had quietly squeezed past the nearest auror and continued spiraling up, occasionally having to duck against the wall to avoid aurors running up or down in no search pattern she could identify.

A few minutes later, she reached the correct level. It was obviously the correct place because of the rain falling into the prison through a roundish hole punched in the ceiling (and outer wall of the corridor above). The auror she'd heard over the mirror had put her phoenix on his shoulder and was trying but failing to look properly heroic while recounting the story to his CO, gesturing at the crumpled halves of a small metal shell. The phoenix somehow had a murderous expression totally incongruous with such an animal. At its first opportunity, the phoenix hopped to the floor and began a slow, furtive escape attempt.

Hermione checked to make sure no one was watching then pulled the edge of the cloak over the phoenix, picked it up, and quickly backed away.

"What the hell did you do?" She whispered, once she was far enough from the aurors.

The phoenix just spread its wings, made eye contact, and slowly shook its head.

"Right. After this, we have to get back to Hogwarts so I can yell at Harry." The phoenix nodded.

They carefully descended through the prison. Past the lowest level, where no humans had likely tread since the prison was constructed, was the threshold through which dementors accessed the prison. Hermione looked into the cave; there was no other way to describe it, there was even a dripping stalactite near the opening. Hermione held her breathe as a dementor drifted by. Once it had passed, the stalactite had a thin layer of ice covering it; the dementor nest was apparently made of permafrost, the obvious result of every other material decaying into dust, mixing with the ever-present rain, and freezing from perpetual dementor exposure.

She took several deep breaths and cast a patronus, then walked to center of the cavern, right into the center of uncounted scores of hovering, cloaked corpses, which quickly became locked in place. She pushed more power into the patronus, which quickly became blindingly bright.

For what felt like a lifetime she felt her life force flowing out of her wand and through the patronus, but she felt something similar flowing back in from both the phoenix and from the dementors as they were vanquished, then overflowing out again. For a moment, Hermione couldn't imagine why she would want to be doing anything else. She pushed even more power through the patronus.

Suddenly the patronus went out. Hermione blinked a few times then noticed that the phoenix had grabbed her wand. The cloaks were lying in the muddy slush, empty.

"Well, that's the biggest check-mark on my to-do list... for my entire life to date. If I were anyone else, I might be concerned about what to follow it up with, but if my life ever gets boring I can just talk to Harry... I guess I should figure out how to get out of here."

This was easier said than done; the phoenix clearly couldn't fly in Azkaban, and a few seconds of testing demonstrated that her broom couldn't either. The weird forces that kept her from running would likely crash an airplane and something like a blimp or hot air balloon would be too easy of a target. Flying away appeared to be impossible.

Although, there were other options. Hermione was reasonably sure she was immune to hypothermia, and even if not, with a phoenix she should still be able to tolerate the water long enough to swim past the wards. Swimming while wearing an invisibility cloak was likely to be problematic but preferable to aurors being able to see her. And if she jumped off the tower through the hole left by her phoenix's arrival, she'd break a few bones but recover quickly enough. It seemed like a viable plan.

She began climbing stairs back to the upper levels but only made it to the second lowest level when she saw aurors. There was a giant spider (nowhere near as large as an acromantula, but still terrifying) behind them, weaving a web across the landing. After it completed the web, they cast a series of wards on it. The web was tightly woven enough to catch even an insect animagus, though casting animagus detection charms would have been far easier. Hermione realized they must have either detected or guessed the presence of the cloak of invisibility, and were prepared to catch a dark wizard with additional options for escape.

After finishing the detection wards on the web the aurors moved down the hallway, stunning the prisoners who Hermione could now hear attempting to escape their cells and fight the aurors. But there were few prisoners this low.

"Oh, no", Hermione whispered. They would seal the lowest level and begin searching it in only another minute. She moved to the center of the corridor, walked into one of the cells and paused to think. She didn't know what wards were cast on the webs or how to bypass them. It was possible she could escape directly, but she didn't know any spells powerful enough to break through the metal walls, especially not quickly enough.

She smiled, "oh, yeah." She drew the rocket launcher from her pouch and fired at the corridor wall. The anti-tank round easily tore a large hole in the structure, allowing rain and light from the overcast sky in. As Hermione got back up from where she'd been blown against the far wall, she made a mental note to always use a blast shield and hearing protection when setting off explosives in the future; she'd been hit by a small amount of shrapnel, which her body quickly expelled, but the burns from the explosion weren't healing as quickly. And not being able to hear anything over the ringing sound was quite annoying.

The aurors heard the explosion and ran toward it from both sides, but Hermione was already in the water, where the phoenix tried to climb onto her back, still tangled in the wet cloak. Hermione slowly swam away from the island, wondering whether unicorns had some prophetic ability. It was improbable to the extreme that the first thing she asked Harry to get after being revived was exactly what she needed on her first mission afterward. Or maybe RPGs are just one of those things that are useful in every situation.

"I don't think we should tell people about you crashing my phoenix. Or me blowing myself up. In the future, when we can talk about all this, I mean. We should just say I... I don't know, flew in and destroyed the dementors with no particular difficulties."

"Yeah, that's probably for the best... Hermione, wait, what do you mean 'crashed'? The parachute failed?"

"There was a parachute?"

"Caw?"

"What do you mean you don't know what a parachute does? I asked if you understood everything and you nodded... Anyway, I don't have time for this. I have to time-turn and test an hypothesis. You might be interested too."

Harry went backwards several hours. Hermione appeared in his office a moment later. They quietly (so as not to disturb past-Harry on the roof) exited the office and walked to the third floor corridor. "So there's a legend that phoenices come from this magic mirror that happens to be in Hogwarts. The mirror has other magic as well, so it would be preferable if we use the invisibility cloak to prevent it from reacting to us."

A few minutes later, they stood invisibly before the mirror. Harry had first noticed the phoenix two minutes from now. They waited. Harry couldn't help trying to count the seconds in his head. He had reached 140 when there was a bright flash of phoenix fire. They found themselves back in Harry's office with the phoenix hovering in front of them.

"Hermione, your phoenix is interfering with science!"

"You asked us to move the prisoners and then less than a week later, the dementors are mysteriously gone? And you don't expect us to suspect that you're involved? How naive do you think we are, Ogden?"

"I'm not an idiot or a vigilante, Umbridge. I objected to torturing prisoners but I never advocated acting against the will of this council nor depriving our country of its dementor deterrent. Your attempt to tie me to this act due to my political beliefs would be disturbing if anyone still took you seriously. Next you'll probably blame me for somehow causing Voldemort to kill all your friends."

Umbridge made an offended noise and turned away, looking up toward the podium. "And you... you told us the prison was more secure than ever. Are we to believe you knew nothing about this?"

Bones frowned. "I can neither confirm nor deny that being Chief Warlock comes with special foreknowledge of crazy crap that's about to happen." Then muttered quietly "I hate this job so much. And that kid."

The headmistress' office was never quiet. Despite having countless silencing charms applied, at least one object was always making noise, even when no one was around. Now, the only sound came from behind the empty desk, where a cube made audible 'blorple' sounds at regular intervals. And a 'click' as the door unlatched and swung slightly ajar before fully opening a second later. A moment later there was another click as the door closed and latched. Then only the sound of the cube remained.

Chapter 8: Planning Ahead

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world, but has made significant progress: Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors, and Bones is grudgingly taking his cues on national policy. Progress toward a functional Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities and a temporary solution is being set up in the now-abandoned Azkaban tower. Harry has built up a relatively long list of things he needs to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, magic-technology interactions, and helping Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like revisiting his conclusions about comed-tea, looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem, and looking into whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped. Moody, Bones, McGonagall, and Hermione were all concerned when Harry advocated releasing Voldemort from the ring in order to question him about the mirror and help rescue Dumbledore.

Sprout has mysteriously received a gift: the long-lost and apparently cursed Hufflepuff Cup and has displayed uncharacteristically aggressive behavior. She had requested Hermione's help with research of a vaguely defined nature. Draco, after having found the Riddle Diary, is showing some very Voldemort-like thoughts and behaviors, working to amass power and followers for himself, and brutally knocking down anyone who gets in his way.

Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. Bellatrix is still at large and able to appear in public despite being Magical Britain's most wanted. The inmate assumed to be Pettigrew has disappeared, leaving questions about his true identity and possible crimes.

"I checked Sprout for evidence of recent legilimency or memory charms and came up empty", Moody began. "Nothing indicating a confundus either, though you wouldn't expect it after several hours. I did see a trace of dark magic, but it wasn't from an imperius. It looked more like an after-effect of possession."

The others stared in silence for a moment, processing the ramifications.

McGonagall spoke first, "So Voldemort isn't defeated after all?"

Moody replied, "He's not the only one in the world who could've made a horcrux and there may be other ways to possess someone with dark magic. But Voldemort is the only one I know for certain has that ability and, of the dark wizards who may be capable of such things, he's the most likely to want to infiltrate Hogwarts." He stared at Harry, "Ring on the table. Now."

While Harry complied. Moody snapped, "We all heard you talk about wanting to let him out. Is there anything you want to tell us?"

Harry sighed, "I know how dangerous Voldemort is and I'm not reckless or insane. I still think we should consider waking him and trying to learn what Interdicted magic he's acquired, but I won't do it unless it's in a heavily-warded area with lots of aurors (and probably trained snipers) ready to act. And unless at least one of you agrees that it was worth the risk."

Moody grunted and ignored everyone for a few minutes while he checked the wards on the ring. Eventually he concluded, "There's no indication that the transfiguration was interrupted or that the wards were tampered with." He turned to Harry, handing back the ring, "How sure are you that Voldie couldn't possess someone with a horcrux while still being trapped in there?"

Harry shook his head, "I don't know exactly how his horcruxen work or what he can do with them. He claimed that they were connected together and kept up-to-date copies of his memories. They should have all been obliviated along with him, but I suppose it's possible he had some safeguard to prevent that. But he also claimed he had the Resurrection Stone, that it would allow him to project a spirit wherever he wished, and that he'd torture everyone I care about. It's been months, so either he's trapped, he lied about his abilities, or he lied about his intentions. How sure are you that Sprout was possessed, rather than exposed to some other dark magic? And more simply, if you scanned a thousand people, how many would you expect to show some trace of dark magic? Is it a perfect indicator that someone's either done something wrong or been victimized, or are there more mundane explanations as well? And if it's a good indicator, why isn't it more common to check for it?"

Bones answered, "You're right; it's not a perfect test. I'll get someone to do some research and try to find a better charm for detecting whether someone has been possessed."

"A spell for locating a disembodied dark wizard or object imbued with dark magic would also be helpful. Unless you already know of one?" Harry asked.

Bones shook her head, "I'll put it on the list. Is there anything else we need to discuss today?"

Moody answered, "There's some good news: the first terminal patients have been treated with the stone. You've probably noticed the new building just outside the wards; it's not being used for anything. I had floo connections set up in a couple abandoned buildings in Muggle London to be the arrival and departure rooms. For now, I'm planning to change the floo code once per week, and the physical location once per month. So far, a few doctors at St. Mungo's and the largest hospitals in France and Ireland are being kept up to date on the floo code for the arrival room. I'm recommending the other hospitals in each region transfer their hardest cases to the largest hospitals to minimize the number of people who need to know there's a secret hospital or how to get to the arrival room.

"And finally, we should really consider meeting somewhere else. Scanning this place for magical traps or listening devices takes forever with all the random magic crap in this office."

Harry smiled, "I recommend my office. You're already scanning it regularly, and this gives me an excuse to get a floo connection installed."

After the meeting, even though Harry didn't believe it probable that Voldemort had returned to Hogwarts, he couldn't stop thinking about ways Voldemort may have escaped or what he would be doing if he had. He didn't sleep well that week.

Robert Jugson, who had avoided the infirmary for most of his years at Hogwarts, had returned for the third time in a single week. "What do you mean you don't have anything for this? You're supposed to have potions for everything. And it itches all the time. I need something."

"I told you: there's nothing physically wrong, so there's nothing I can treat. But I can give you a potion for anxiety."

"I'm not crazy! It's real- what about this rash?" He pulls back his sleeve, showing red marks across his upper arm. "It's even started bleeding."

"It looks like you did that to yourself by scratching. I can give you a skin repairing salve but you should start taking a calming potion."

"What about these things coming out of the cuts?"

She waves here wand and mutters an analytic charm, "They're fabric fibers. From your robes or bedsheets or something."

Jugson cursed under his breath and left the hospital wing. Draco, who had been in the hallway nearby, started walking alongside him, "I've heard about your recent problems. I assume you've started planning revenge on him."

"What?! Who? Not Sloper, he's just as bad off."

"You were with Sloper after hours. And you apparently weren't fighting each other. How many interests do you have in common with him? It's not hard to guess what you were doing."

Jugson stopped and faced Draco, scowling and crossing his arms menacingly.

Draco ignored this and continued, "So ask yourself: of all the people you know, who would have fought you, especially with such an unconventional attack? Who's famous for doing whatever the hell he feels like and getting away with it?"

Jugson's eyes widened, "Potter! ...Wait, I thought he was your friend."

Draco shrugged, "There were hints from the beginning that he's going to be a powerful dark lord. I was prepared to support him. I intended to ride that power to the top. I'm sure you understand. But he's always used my offers of friendship to manipulate me when it's in his interest and ignored me when I suppose I'm not providing enough value or amusement. If he acts this way as a 12 year old...", Draco shuddered, "some day, this country will be covered with mass graves, containing his former enemies and former allies alike."

"Someone should stop him before it's too late."

Draco nodded. "I intend to do what I can, but it's going to take some time to build support and devise a plan. Can I count on your support when it's time?"

"...so it's not that Lockhart didn't make some good points, I'm just not looking forward to learning pointless minutia about things that aren't dangerous to anyone with a quantum of common sense", Harry concluded.

Penelope Clearwater nodded, "It's not surprising you feel that way. Those of us who have been at Hogwarts longer remember some of the truly incompetent Defense professors. You've not only been spoiled by a having a good one, he also kind of wanted to be a dark lord, much like yourself, so it's pretty unlikely you'll have another Defense professor that you like as well as Professor Quirrell."

Harry shrugged, "Whatever. Anyway, I'll find a way to make the class educational even if I have to teach Professor Lockhart the true meaning of chaos. Especially if."

Suddenly distracted, Harry opened his notebook and sighed. He turned it toward Hermione and quietly said, "I've forgotten to do most of my comed-tea tests this week. Could you start reminding me at dinner? I'll find another memory aid too. That should provide enough redundancy to perform the experiment."

Hermione just shrugged.

After a pause, Padma said, "Speaking of chaos in the Defense class, the first year class must have been pretty entertaining. I heard Luna tried to convince the professor that people can use the killing curse without hating the target."

Harry managed to not choke, but frowned at Luna, "Why would you say that?"

"Because it's true, of course. Although I suppose you meant to ask why I would give that information to anyone. I didn't really think of that at the time; it was just so peculiar that the Defense Against the Dark Arts Professor didn't know better."

Across the Great Hall, Draco decided to spend more time observing Harry Potter's activities. He slowly drew his wand and subtly cast a directional hearing charm. He kept his head down and pretended to focus on his meal while trying to keep his ear correctly angled to overhear Potter's conversation.

"...be surprising. Anyone can teach the material in a textbook. Professor Lockhart may have been on some cool adventures, but that doesn't mean he knows much about the Dark Arts. It's been suggested that he's been relying on a supply of Felix Felicis to do everything he's..."

Draco winced and canceled the charm as some yelling idiot walked into his line-of-hearing. No matter; that had been surprisingly informative for what was probably a generic conversation about coursework. He resolved to be extremely careful around Lockhart, and finalized his potion-brewing plans. Several useful potions take quite a while to brew, and any intelligent person starts preparing such things well before one needs them...

"So you think you're better at flying than me?", Ron yelled, interrupting the Ravenclaws' discussion. Harry calmly took a bite of food without looking up. "Hey, I'm talking to you, Potter!"

Harry swallowed the food and slowly turned, "Am I just supposed to assume you're talking to me whenever you yell something?" He deliberately looked down at his watch, "I really don't have the time for that; I'm a busy person, you know."

"You think you're better at flying than me!"

Harry rolled his eyes, "I was last year, but it's not like I've spent much time practicing. So now, who knows."

Ginny, who had followed her brother from the Gryffindor table, helpfully added, "Ron's about to try out for the Gryffindor quidditch team. A group of Slytherins keep telling everyone that if he makes the team, then with you, Gregory, and Cedric on the other teams, Gryffindor will come in last place."

Harry glared at Ron, "That doesn't explain why he's yelling at me instead of at them."

Ron clarified, "Are you going to race me or not?"

Harry replied, "Why not? Just write out all the rules, like what brooms we have to use, the course you want to follow, any areas that are out of bounds, how the start of the race will be indicated, who will judge or otherwise how we determine the winner, etc. and get it to me at least a week before the actual race so I can go over it."

"Rules? Why can't we just race?"

"If there aren't written rules, then if I win, you'll accuse me of cheating. You'll claim that some random thing or another was obviously against the unspecified rules and demand a rematch. I'm skipping that part and requiring the rules to be specified in advance."

Ron stared at Harry and muttered, "I challenge him to a race and he gives me bloody homework."

Harry turned his back on Ron, "Hermione, do you want to work on another electronics experiment? I'm thinking about walking around just inside the Hogwarts wards to see if my watch or calculator will turn on anywhere."

Hermione replied, "I'm really busy; there are some things I really need to work on. And do you really think that's a two person job?"

Harry shrugged, "Honestly, I just can't remember the last time you went outside. And today might be the last time the weather is this nice until spring."

Ginny interjected, "I can help!"

"Hermione's right; it really isn't a two person job. And I don't think it has a high likelihood of producing novel data anyway." Harry pushed his plate away and stood up.

"But that's the same reason why we should race now!", Ron argued.

Harry smirked as he walked away.

"... And that's why you should always wear gloves and eye protection when working with acid slugs", Lockhart concluded. Read and summarize chapter two from the standard text and begin reading my Guide to Household Pests by next week.

While everyone was leaving , Harry walked to the professor's desk. "I need to borrow a target drone."

"What?"

"The spheres stored in the ceiling that are charmed to float around and absorb spells for people practicing dueling. I need to borrow one for... a project in another class."

Lockhart glanced at the ceiling, noticing the hatch for the first time, then looked at Harry and smiled, "Let me guess: after Professor Quirrell's class, you're disappointed that you haven't gotten to shoot anyone or anything in Defense class this year, and you want to practice on your own?"

"It really is for another class... but you're not wrong."

Lockhart cast a levitation charm and pulled at the hatch in the ceiling while talking, "Well, you can take a target if you like, but you should know, I do have some ideas for more... hands-on activities for class." The hatch finally fell open and Lockhart cast a quick accio, pulling out one of the spheres.

"Such as?"

He smiled wider, "I wouldn't want to spoil the surprise." He handed Harry the sphere.

Harry nodded, put the target drone in his pouch, and walked away.

Chapter 9: Philosophy (Omake)

Harry and Luna Discuss Philosophy for Some Reason (Omake)

"This feels like the start of a new chapter", Luna stated.

Padma asked, "You mean, like things are changing? I remember feeling like that when I first came to Hogwarts."

"I meant the story that we're in just turned a page and started a new chapter, with a new number and title and everything. It's odd though; I'm not sure what the number is."

"Luna, this isn't a story. This is the real world", Hermione said slowly.

Luna looked at Hermione and tilted her head, "What do you think you know and how do you think you know it?"

Harry smiled, showing his teeth, then added, "Heroes and villains with magic and monsters and in a castle and with noble titles; it sounds like a story, doesn't it."

Hermione frowned at Harry, "You're not having trouble with the difference between reality and fantasy are you? Because you getting schizophrenia would be really, really bad."

"If you're living in a story, then the story is real to you", Luna added helpfully.

Padma shook her head, "No, no, no, no, no. It was bad enough last week when Harry tried to convince us we're probably all living inside of a muggle computer; don't you start trying to convince us we're fictional characters."

Harry lectured, "That's the result of a straightforward application of Bayes' Rule, with some reasonable assumptions about a mature civilization's ability to simulate intelligent beings and the number of simulated intelligences that would be created by a typical civilization, both directly and recursively. And when the existence of magic is added to the calculation, it raises the probability that all of this is a simulation even more."

Luna replied, "And what happens to that calculation when you use the number of stories and characters instead of simulations and simulated people? I think there are more of those."

"That's different; the characters in stories aren't conscious like we are", Hermione challenged.

"So you're an expert on detecting consciousness now?" Harry teased. "Then tell me, is there something so special about calcium ion channels and neurotransmitters?"

Hermione sighed, "I guess I could believe that a simulation could be conscious, but not a fictional character."

"So then, if you're okay with a conscious mind based on meat or one based on silicon, does it matter if the computer is made of something else; vacuum tubes or electromagnetic relays, for example?"

"I suppose not."

"Then what about something more exotic? It's been proposed that in any given universe Boltzmann brains will vastly outnumber evolved intelligences. They're created by quantum fluctuations in cold gas that randomly happen to produce a self-aware entity for the short period of time they remain intact."

"You don't really believe that, do you?" Padma asked. Hermione also looked skeptical.

Harry waved dismissively, "Then forget that. Take the computer simulation and imagine that, instead of a physical computer, there's a person doing the calculations, whether they're encoding the results with a pencil and paper or maybe by lining up rocks in an extremely large plain."

Hermione looked thoughtful, "Maybe the rule should be that conscious entities can use any physical structure, unless it requires another conscious entity; then its thoughts are really part of that entity's consciousness."

"That doesn't work", Harry replied. "Imagine you're doing a pencil-and-paper simulation of two entities having a conversation in Chinese. You don't know Chinese, right? You could simulate the entire conversation without having any idea what it was about. So those entities' thoughts wouldn't exist in your own mind."

"Oh. That's just strange. I don't think it's right."

"I think part of the problem is that it's easy to imagine consciousness being located inside of a brain or even a processor, but it's hard to imagine consciousness located on a piece of paper or in a graphite smudge."

Hermione nodded.

"But you could simulate an entity using multiple computers networked together; for example, with its visual cortex in one country and a cell cluster from its left frontal lobe in another. Any time you believed you knew where the conscious part was, you could physically separate those calculations and repeat until each computer simulated a single cell. Or atom. It's an error to picture consciousness located at any specific physical location."

Hermione replied, "I don't know. Something has to be wrong with that; I just haven't thought of what yet."

Padma concluded, "I think you're all nuts. I'm going to assume only humans and human-like creatures can be intelligent or conscious until I meet something else that acts like it."

"It is difficult to picture the causal relationship between writing numbers on paper and a conscious entity's thoughts. So maybe simulating the math at a low level isn't really necessary; maybe it's enough to develop a universe and a character and write their thoughts and behavior."

"Where and how are you drawing a line between the plausible and the ridiculous scenarios you've mentioned? Or do you think everything is conscious, and that Luna's right that we're more likely to be in a story than in real life?"

"It does seem silly that fictional characters (or pencil-and-paper simulated entities) would produce consciousness. Maybe it's all about the mathematics; for any mathematically consistent universe that would produce intelligent beings, those beings are conscious and aware of that universe, whether anyone's simulating it or not. That also solves the problem of where everything came from: it doesn't have to come from anywhere, it just has to be logically consistent."

Padma shook her head, "I can't tell if you're being serious or not."

Harry smiled, "Yeah, I'm not really sure anymore."

"I'm not really sure, either", added the author.

Chapter 14: More Questions Than Answers

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world, but has made significant progress: Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors. Progress toward a functional Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities but a temporary solution is operational in the now-abandoned Azkaban tower.

Sprout received a cursed Hufflepuff Cup, and displayed uncharacteristically aggressive behavior afterwards. Moody detected evidence of dark magic on her but it was inconclusive. Since then, Moody has researched more specific spells for detecting horcrux effects and, as one might expect, Hermione tested positive. Harry thought of some potential countermeasures Voldemort could have used against parseltongue and obliviation and began to suspect that Voldemort's plan had been to pretend to lose while preparing a powerful and immortal host for himself who Harry would trust implicitly (and explicitly, given the unbreakable vow). Unfortunately, that same vow has prevented him from sharing his suspicions. Draco found the Riddle Diary, which then passed through a series of other people, affecting their behavior and leaving evidence of memory charms behind. Moody and McGonagall set up a test to find anyone affected and locate the artifact presumed responsible.

Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. And obviously plotting something. Bellatrix is still at large and able to appear in public despite topping Magical Britain's most wanted list.

Harry has a relatively long list of things he intends to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, time-turner paradoxes, magic-technology interactions, and rescuing Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem or whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped, so he has focused more strongly on learning arithmancy, which involves putting spells together to achieve novel functions.

Harry sighed. His attempt to apply epidemiological principles (as if a horcrux were a mere infectious disease) had not been particularly successful. Things had looked hopeful; the assumed horcrux had followed a logical path for a time. Progressing from Draco to other second-year Slytherins made sense. Daphne and Tracey were evidently best friends and where therefore frequently together. The progression from Daphne to Lavender made similar sense.

But that was it. Harry had advised Moody to expect some other second year Slytherins or possibly former Dragon Army lieutenants to show evidence of memory charms, because the horcrux should have been somewhere before it passed to Draco. Harry would have bet on Gregory or Vincent showing symptoms. Similarly, Harry had advised that Lavender was most likely to have passed the horcrux to Parvati, Padma, Susan, or Hannah. Or possibly to another second-year Gryffindor. Or someone from the Sunshine Regiment.

But no. Moody had polyjuiced as Madame Pomfrey and had scanned every student under the guise of checking for Dragon Pox. No one had shown a trace of legilimency, memory charms, or obliviation. There was no dark magic on the students or their luggage. One of the invisible aurors was a specialist curse-breaker who could find and open magically hidden compartments in seconds without leaving a trace. The number of banned objects he had reported shocked McGonagall but none of it had been worth exposing the search for. Moody had then run down Lockhart and scanned him, over his objections that he was in a hurry to catch a port-key to Australia (and some rambling about hunting drop-bears). Moody had reluctantly let him go ("Another ten minutes, and I'm sure I would've found evidence of something illegal he's mixed up in", Moody had insisted) and the aurors had returned to their normal duties.

McGonagall had then asked the house elves to search the school for apparently lost or hidden objects and bring them to her office. As a result, there was a pile next to her desk containing assorted textbooks, parchments, quills, a couple of gloves, and a shoe ("How does a student lose a shoe?" she had exclaimed). And then Moody had insisted that she order the elves to line up in a corridor so he could verify that none of them had been affected by the horcrux. There had been no new hint about where the horcrux had come from, where it had gone, nor how or even whether Professor Sprout had been involved. Harry sighed again. It was likely that they were chasing a false horcrux; that Voldemort had faked it in the form of an unsolvable puzzle to confuse anyone investigating him (or to mess with Harry, specifically).

"Harry!" Petunia ran across the room to hug him.

"Hi, mum! Hi, Dad!" Michael had entered, carrying a large box, "Oh, books!" Harry ran over and peeked into the box.

McGonagall entered behind them, "Isn't it traditional to wait until Christmas day to exchange presents?"

Michael shrugged, "We've always done presents at the earliest time it was convenient. Never seemed rational to wait longer than that."

"The keypunch and punch-cards I was expecting. You got me a microscope?"

"It's not electronic, so it should work. Hopefully it will be useful."

Harry nodded, "Your new books are in the box over there. It's mostly wizard history and fiction. There are a few that cover hypotheses about the nature of magic. They might be interesting, but it's important to remember that their authors don't actually know anything."

"Magic violates conservation of mass-energy and momentum, right?"

"Apparently."

"Any of their ideas have a solution for that?"

"Somehow I doubt they see it as a problem."

"Well, I consider it a problem; physics can't be that wrong. It can't be a coincidence that all the experimental tests have backed the Standard Model. I've been wondering whether the solution might involve dark matter. When there are phenomena that appear to create mass, and 75% of the mass in the universe is practically undetectable, it makes sense to look for a connection. When we say dark matter only interacts gravitationally, maybe we should really be saying it only interacts gravitationally or magically."

"Or if gravity is a form of magic that just happens to be particularly well-behaved and easy to detect, that might explain why general relativity and quantum theory have been so hard to unify."

"Or the missing solar neutrinos might be part of it. At some point, you should see if you can get a few thousand wizards to cast spells simultaneously to see if a neutrino detector picks up a difference. There's a testable prediction..."

McGonagall looked questioningly at Petunia, who smiled and shrugged. McGonagall shrugged back, turned and walked away.

Harry sneezed once again as he walked into the hospital wing.

Madame Pomfrey looked up at him, and Harry asked, "What do you have for an upper respiratory inf-". The rest was cut off as Harry started coughing.

She handed him a glass of water, while motioning for him to sit. She then waved her wand over him and muttered a few spells.

"Pepper-up potion will clear that up quickly enough. I'll give you a dose; take it about half-an-hour before you plan to sleep. Also, you appear to be sleep deprived, so you need to make an effort to get more sleep. That is especially important for people who have had their sleep cycle lengthened. The lack of sleep makes you more susceptible to every illness that passes through the school."

"Thank you for the potion. I'll make an effort to get more sleep."

Dean approached Harry as he was leaving the great hall after dinner, "Hey, I did that experiment; I brought a digital watch back and observed where it stopped working. I also brought records back."

"Great, I'll get the record player stuff and a map. I think visualizing the places where electronics will and won't work might be helpful." He ran off.

Dean was about to call after him, then shrugged and walked back toward the Gryffindor rooms, "He really doesn't need to make things this difficult."

A few minutes later, Harry approached the Gryffindor common room, when he had a thought that could be best expressed as, "Crap. Password." He then slowly smiled, and muttered, "It would be a shame not to try it." He touched his wand to his robes and transfigured it such that the colored parts were red and gold. He quickly glanced around the corner to locate the portrait that guarded the door and cast, 'quietus' at it.

He casually walked up to the door and the woman in the portrait silently mouthed some kind of greeting or challenge. Harry began, "So this is the entrance to Gryffindor and there's a password. Obviously, being a Gryffindor, I know the password, and it probably isn't a very secure password. It might have something to do with phoenices or fighting Slytherins or stupid heroics or something. A Gryffindor password would be something like that. Or some other word. There are so many words, because English took lots of words from German and French and other languages."

During this time, the two-dimensional woman had held her hands to her ears and strained to listen carefully, then attempted to clean her ears, and finally began to look annoyed. She mouthed something Harry didn't catch.

Harry stopped talking for a moment, during which he forced himself to look progressively more concerned. Then he asked "Why aren't you opening the door?"

The portrait's expression changed from annoyed to confused. She appeared to say, "I can't hear."

Harry forced himself to look panicked and began repeating, "Why won't you open the door? You have to open the door."

The door unlatched and the woman hurried to the side, past the portrait's frame. Harry walked in.

Dean looked over, mildly surprised, "How did you get in here?"

"I snapped my fingers."

"No, really."

"Social engineering."

"Whatever. Anyway, before you ran off, I was going to tell you not to bother with the map. The watch worked fine until the carriage got to the bridge in front of the castle. Then it turned off and didn't come back on."

Harry frowned, "You mean it worked on platform nine-point-seven-five? And on the train? It only stopped inside the Hogwarts wards?"

"Yes. Clearly you were expecting something more complicated?"

"Well, yes. That contradicts previous results." Harry pulled out a calculator, "I couldn't get this to turn on the last time I was at the train platform."

Percy interrupted, "Why are you wearing Gryffindor robes?"

Harry suppressed a smirk and mentally canceled the transfiguration, then looked down at himself, "They look the same as usual to me." He turned to Dean, "They look like Ravenclaw robes to you right?" Dean nodded. Harry turned back to Percy, "Maybe you're under a confundus charm?"

"Cute." He gestured at the calculator, "You know that won't work in the castle, right?"

Harry nodded and Dean answered, "Harry's been trying to figure out where it works and where it doesn't. But it sounds like the places where technology works change. Sort of like the hallways here; maybe you have to figure out a different map for Mondays vs. Fridays and everything."

Percy's expression brightened noticeably, "My father actually has a calculator that looks similar to that one; he said it makes it bearable to keep the budget for his department at the Ministry. He's done quite a bit of work with muggle electronics, and might know something about that. He'd probably also be interested in hearing about what you've tried so far."

"That... sounds really useful. Ask him to send me an owl and we can start exchanging results."

Percy nodded then walked away.

"So what did you come up with to play a record?"

Harry pulled an irregularly shaped wooden box out of his pouch. It had an open front, though its most notable feature was a turntable on its top surface. Harry then retrieved a car battery and a motor and placed them inside the box.

"That looks like it's made from a desk from one of the classrooms", Dean observed.

"It contains parts from several desks, actually. I imagine the house elves were pretty confused when they had to clean up that mess." While talking, Harry attached a variable resistor to the battery and motor using alligator clips. The turntable began spinning slowly.

"It doesn't exactly look like a professional setup."

"How many professionals are there at combining magic with muggle technology?"

"Fair point." Dean shrugged and placed a record carefully onto the turntable.

Harry pulled a metal bar from his pouch, affixed one end to the box, and carefully lowered the other onto the record.

Dean watched expectantly, then commented, "I think you need an amplifier and speakers and I don't see how you're going to connect them to that."

"A speaker is basically just a cone that vibrates to cause the air in front of it to vibrate. Sound is just vibrating air. The grooves of a record cause the needle to vibrate according to the sounds it stores. This needle is mechanically linked little cones here and here; it doesn't need electronics."

Dean stepped forward and looked carefully at the needle, "That's not going to be very loud."

Harry pointed his wand at the record player, "Sonorus." A low pitched hum became audible. He swung his wand around to point left, "Ventriliquo." He cast the same pair of spells, this time pointing to the right. "There's a 50% chance I got the left and right channels correct. If you decide it's backwards, switch the sides when you cast it next time." He then picked up the variable resistor and turned the knob, speeding up the motor. The hum rose in pitch until it resolved into music and singing. "That sounds about right", Harry concluded.

"Do I have to worry about maintaining a transfiguration on the parts or something?"

"No, they're permanent."

"Please don't try to tell me you can make transfigurations permanent by snapping your fingers."

Harry smiled, "That would be a useful skill. Actually, there's an advanced free transfiguration technique called shaping that lets you specify how the initial object turns into the final object. For example, you can take a sphere and make the outer layer turn into the left side of a rod, then make the inside turn into the right side of the rod. If you cut the rod in half and reverse the transfiguration, the left half becomes a hollow sphere and the right half is the part that would have been the inside. Or you can transfigure something into paper and cut out the pattern you need; that's what I did for these parts."

At this point, Fred announced loudly, "Cool, random party!"

George followed up with, "The butter-beer and sweets are over here."

Percy frowned, "Why do you two have all of that?"

"It's important to be prepared for these things."

Percy shrugged, "It's the first night back from the break, so I suppose it's okay. Just don't make a habit of it."

"Of course, Percy. We would never want to interfere with the monotony of the Hogwarts experience."

Percy shook his head and hid a smile as he walked away.

Harry approached Fred and George, "Hey, are you guys interested in helping me with a prank?"

"Do you even have to ask?"

"Not so fast, George. It's important that we get some details first. We don't attach our brand to anything too mundane or derivative."

Fred nodded, "You're absolutely correct, Fred." They looked at Harry seriously.

Harry waited.

After a few seconds, they started laughing and simultaneously asked, "What do you need?"

Hermione sat next to Harry at breakfast and asked, "Do you want to go to the quidditch match today?"

"No more than usual, why?"

"Well, I feel like I should see at least one during my time at Hogwarts. Who knows, maybe it will be interesting. And I heard the Ravenclaw and Slytherin seekers deliberately ignored the snitch to run up the score last year. What did they ever do to fix that?"

"I don't know. That was a somewhat eventful day, and I kind of stopped following the whole thing after that. I suppose we could go, if you'd like, though I'd preferred if you'd chosen a nice day, rather than the middle of January when it looks like we'll be getting a blizzard."

"Well, then maybe we can teach the children of the magical community about sledding."

Harry laughed, then stopped when he realized Hermione didn't. "Uh... sure, we can watch a quidditch game."

Harry brushed the snow off a seat and sat down, "Ugh. I guess I'll be trying to use arithmancy to optimize the warming charm for the next hour."

Hermione just smiled at him.

"You should probably at least pretend to be cold."

"Yeah, probably."

Another group of students walked over. Daphne looked at the seats, then at the field, and announced, "This is ridiculous. I'm going back inside."

Tracey added, "Yeah, me too. Hermione, you picked the worst possible day to watch your first quidditch game."

Susan scoffed, "This isn't nearly as bad as when it's cold and rainy. Some people just aren't real fans."

Hannah shrugged, "Well, Slytherin isn't playing today."

Harry frowned, "They should really get view screens like Professor Quirrell used in his classes or battles. We're not going to be able to see much out here today."

Lavender sighed, "There has got to be a spell to fix weather like this."

Harry looked thoughtful, "I think if there were weather modification spells, we'd have heard about it by now. Unless they're covered by the Interdict of Merlin. Although, we should probably check the library just in case."

Lavender added, "Well, someone needs to hurry up and invent one. And I'm looking at you, General Chaos. Get on that."

Hermione snickered then suggested, "Maybe they have a spell to blow the snow away or something."

Padma answered, "If they do, I've never seen it before."

Hermione nodded and was about to reply when Lee Jordan's amplified voice filled the stands, "Welcome, ladies and gentlemen, to today's game between the Ravenclaw and Hufflepuff house teams. The snitch is away and the quaffle will be released in thirty seconds, so find a seat if you haven't already. Neither team has yet been mathematically eliminated from winning the House Cup, though really, don't we all know which team-"

McGonagall interrupted, "Mr. Jordan, what have I told you about showing favoritism in your announcing?"

"Keep it subtle rather than blatant?"

"I'm quite sure I never said that."

"Well, it's what I heard. Anyway, the quaffle is in the air, and Ravenclaw appears to have possession, based on the yellow and blue blurs racing toward the Hufflepuff goal."

As the game continued, Harry pondered why they were here. It was out of character for Hermione, so hilariously out of character that no one attempting to model Hermione's behavior would have made such a mistake. The obvious answer was that Hermione/Voldemort was plotting something and needed Harry to be otherwise occupied. No, that wasn't it; it would have been easier to convince him to spend the day in his office (or in the library if the plot was happening in his office). A better answer was that she wanted a public alibi. Though anyone who both knew Hermione and knew about time-turners would be more suspicious of her after learning that her alibi involved a quidditch game.

Lee's voice sounded again, "Due to the poor weather and visibility, and general weakness of character, the members of both teams have elected to end the game after the first team reaches 100 points, breaking centuries of wizarding tradition, causing the quidditch players of prior eras to spin in their graves and bringing dishonor to Ravenclaw and Hufflepuff for the next three generations-"

McGonagall interrupted, "Mr. Jordan, no one is dishonored over a friendly school game."

"Really? You can say that with a straight face?"

"At least tell them the real reason."

"Ugh, fine. The official story is that someone (who we're expected to believe is not working for either team) cast a spell to locate the snitch and found it to be immobile on the ground outside the stadium. An attempt to accio it failed, implying that it's frozen to the ground. Of course, the casual use of two spells which are (for obvious reasons) banned for quidditch matches, raises disturbing questions. I assure you all that this announcer-slash-quidditch-investigative-reporter will be looking into who is casting these spells during games, and what surreptitious methods they're using to communicate that information to whichever seeker is paying the largest bribes-"

"Please spread conspiracy theories on your own time, Mr. Jordan."

"Oh, believe me, I will-"

"And refrain from doing so during games. Especially when you heard me cast the detection spell after a request to do so by both seekers. And you are aware that there are wards preventing cheating by both the players and spectators."

"You heard it here first, folks: the scandal goes all the way to the top!"

Eventually, Lee announced, "Yay! The game is finally over! Neither team actually 'wins' because they were playing by crazy definitely-not-quidditch rules, but we all win because we can go back inside!"

Hermione asked the group, "Hey, does anyone feel like walking around the lake?"

There were several objections of the "frostbite and hypothermia sound unpleasant" variety, after which Hermione announced that she hadn't spent enough time outside recently and was going anyway. The others went back to the castle.

Once inside, Ron approached and quietly said, "Remember Operation Firebolt." He quickly walked away.

The others looked at each other questioningly. Lavender answered, "Secret Gryffindor business. You don't need to know." She and Parvati left before anyone could ask a follow-up question.

Harry shook his head, "I should probably look into that, but I'm way behind on my to-do list for today. And I have a feeling that I really don't want to know."

After Harry walked to his office, he tried to think of an excuse he could give for an auror to follow Hermione without raising suspicions. By the time he reached the office, he had eliminated most of the options he'd considered. He was about to sit down, when he jumped back suddenly and pulled out a communications mirror, "Hey, Mad-Eye, I think someone tampered with my office. When you get a chance-"

"Well, don't touch anything. In fact, wait outside. I'll be there in a few minutes."

An hour or two later, Moody had scanned nearly everything in the office for magical traces without finding anything suspicious.

Moody's head snapped up and to the side as he exclaimed, "What the fuck?" Harry followed his gaze to... an ordinary looking area of the ceiling. Meanwhile, Moody pulled a small object out of his robes, which quickly expanded into a broom. He flew up the stairs and out of the tower.

Harry pulled a broom out of his pouch and followed, only to see Moody staring out into the dark.

"Dammit!", Moody exclaimed. He spun around and raced toward the astronomy tower. Harry began to follow until Moody shouted back, "Go back inside."

Moody sighed, "I've officially gotten old. There was a time I would have dropped both of them and damn the consequences. Now I'm all worried about putting students in danger."

McGonagall frowned, "Feeling a sense of responsibility is not a bad thing."

Bones commented, "I'm just surprised you didn't have a fast enough broom to intercept them. Normally, you're prepared for things like that."

Moody scoffed, "I have one of the fastest racing brooms you can get. Unfortunately, those smugglers had a dragon pulling them. If there were a broom that could intercept a dragon, I would own one."

"A dragon! Where the hell did a dragon come from?"

McGonagall sighed, "Alastor caught Lavender Brown, Parvati Patil, and Ronald Weasley at the astronomy tower. I interviewed them and from what I've put together, the grounds keeper, Hagrid, raised it from an egg. Weasley's older brother works at a dragon preserve, and sent some of his co-workers to take the dragon somewhere where it will be cared for. Hagrid's on his way here."

Moody nodded, "Good. I have some veritaserum. We can do a proper interrogation."

McGonagall asked, "Are you sure that's strictly necessary?"

"Of course."

Harry added, "I agree."

Bones nodded as well, "After the last time we interviewed that man, truth serum can only speed things up."

There was a knock at the door, and McGonagall called, "Come in, Hagrid."

Moody was ready with a glass of water with two drops of veritaserum dissolved in it. Hagrid looked around at the others, then reluctantly drank it.

"Where did the dragon come from?" Moody began.

"Someone I met at Hogsmeade had a dragon egg he was trying to find a home for. I'd always wanted a dragon, so it worked out for both of us."

Harry asked, "Is it common for people to give away dragon eggs?"

Bones answered, "No, it's utterly ridiculous. Dragons are carefully regulated; every dragon in Britain should be registered. Even if someone has a permit to raise them, they are extremely expensive. And they're not common on the black market because it's difficult to hatch the eggs and there's nowhere to hide an adult dragon. So Mr. Hagrid, what did you pay for that egg?"

"I didn't pay. He gave it to me... Though now that I think about it, he asked me a lot of questions I probably shouldn't have answered."

"Such as?"

"Well, I'd recently picked up something from Gringotts for Dumbledore. He asked about that." Hagrid paused, then looked over at Harry, "He also asked some things about Harry. I don't remember exactly what, but I hadn't met him yet and couldn't really say much."

Bones looked thoughtful, "I'd assume that was Voldemort. Or a death eater."

Harry nodded, "Could be. My guess would be polyjuiced Lucius. Or someone working for Lucius; maybe someone from the Daily Prophet."

Bones turned back to Hagrid, "And you thought you could actually get away with raising a dragon?"

"I really wanted one, so I brought it back here. I got some books on dragon care., and it seemed doable enough."

Harry had a sudden thought, "Auror Moody said dragons are faster than any broom. How fast is a dragon?"

Hagrid appeared to relax a little, "They can get going pretty fast in level flight, but a dragon pulling out of a powered dive can chase down nearly anything."

Harry continued, "Including unicorns?"

Hagrid flinched, "It's happened once that I'm aware of."

Bones narrowed her eyes, "Here? Earlier this year?"

"Yeah. I thought I was feeding it enough, but it decided to hunt. And there are so many unicorns out there now."

McGonagall asked, "And that's why you decided to relocate it?"

"Yeah. Not enough for it to eat here, and not enough room for it, not without getting discovered."

Moody grunted and asked, "What other dangerous animals do you have out there that no one else knows about?"

"I suppose that depends on what you mean by 'dangerous'."

Harry clarified, "Have you brought anything alive onto the Hogwarts grounds without explicit permission?"

Hagrid sighed, "Well there's the acromantulas. And my brother, Grawp. I'm pretty sure Dumbledore knew he was living out there, but he never actually said it was okay."

"Acromantulas!", exclaimed several people.

"How did you get an acromantula past the wards?", Moody demanded.

"I don't know exactly. Dippet was headmaster at the time, and I don't think he was as good as Dumbledore at reading the wards."

McGonagall replied, "I can believe that. I don't think I can sense a tenth of what Dumbledore could from the wards. But Hagrid, why would you bring acromantulas here?"

"I was trying to keep him safe. Wizards tend to be... unfriendly to everyone who's different or who they don't understand. Believe me, I've seen it closer than I'd have liked. You also usually tend to kill things when they're labeled 'dangerous creatures'."

Moody stared at him, "Acromantulas eat people when they get the opportunity. What's your definition of dangerous?"

"Acromantulas are basically people with extra legs. They're smart; they can even learn English. Sure, they eat other animals for food, but so do people."

"And how many are there now?"

"I don't know exactly. Probably hundreds."

Moody just shook his head. Bones mumbled, "You moron."

McGonagall asked, "Is there anything else we should know? Or that you think we'd want to know?"

"Er, I don't think so."

The floo lit up, and Bones stated, "An auror is coming to take you to a detainment room until we decide what to do with you. Or in case we have follow-up questions."

An auror stepped into the room and led Hagrid back out.

Harry spoke first, "How did Hagrid ever get a job here?"

McGonagall answered, "He knows magical creatures really well. And he's a good man. He was an ally during the wizarding war and a friend of both myself and Dumbledore. And your parents. He's just made some mistakes. He doesn't have the best judgment."

"Well, he needs someone with at least a hint of common sense to babysit him whenever he's on the grounds. Or better, everywhere."

Moody chuckled, "Who should we get to clean out the acromantulas? There are a few rookie aurors who could use some practical experience."

Harry frowned, "Is it true that they're sentient?"

Moody shrugged, "They're pretty smart for magical creatures I suppose. I've never heard one talk and I don't think they have near-human intelligence though."

"Then I'd prefer to relocate them somewhere where they aren't a threat to anyone. Where are they originally from?"

McGonagall replied, "South America, I believe. I think most of them live in a nature preserve in Brazil."

"So we could transfer them there?"

Bones answered, "We could probably arrange that with the Brazilians. Safely moving hundreds of giant, hostile spiders, on the other hand, sounds... tedious."

Harry smirked, "Luckily there's a world-famous expert in handling dangerous creatures right here at Hogwarts."

Moody slowly smiled, "That's something I want to see. Oh, tell him he can write his next book about it, maybe 'Arresting Acromantulas'."

Harry replied, "Or 'Sequestering Spiders'."

"'Wrestling Web-builders'."

"'Arachnid Attacks'."

Bones rolled her eyes, "Since we're apparently done with the meeting part of this meeting, I'm going. Minerva, let me know when you decide what you want to do with Hagrid. Or his brother. I consider this a Hogwarts matter, so I'll defer to your judgment."

Harry left the meeting in deep thought. Hagrid and the dragon were responsible for the death of the unicorn, which they had previously attributed to a dark wizard. Because he had considered the unicorn to be evidence that Voldemort was at Hogwarts, that probability was now necessarily lower, so he had to reevaluate the evidence and determine whether it was still rational to believe in Voldemort's continued presence.

The explosion in the potions class could have been an evil plot, but it could have also been an accident (it was astounding how some students could manage to blow up even the safest potions) or a reckless attempt to make the potions class more exciting, producing a larger bang than expected. Students had recently cast 'obliviate', but it was possible that students were learning it and using it on each other to avoid being caught or punished for whatever else they were doing. Any number of students had a motive for the spider-based attack on Jugson and Sloper. Memory charms had been used then as well, but there was apparently a learning curve to reading the wards. It was possible that the spell had triggered the wards, but McGonagall hadn't yet known enough to be aware of it. Harry made a note to ask her about it

Sprout was harder to explain, but there were too many unknowns to infer very much. The detection of 'dark magic' had raised more questions than answers about what a trace of dark magic was or what it meant. The memories Moody had read from Draco were the best evidence of Voldemort, but pointed to an original-recipe horcrux, not a contemporary immortal Voldemort horcrux. Memory charms by a reasonably well informed or creative individual could have also sufficed. The Malfoy family still had enemies, and an apparent Voldemort possession, if made public, could ensure that Draco would never consolidate much political power by raising suspicion that he was a death eater or Voldemort himself.

Voldemort- just because it was possible that one might use a horcrux network to escape obliviation and capture didn't mean Voldemort had that ability. Voldemort's final hours could have been a diabolical plan disguised by pretending to lose, but it also could have been a real defeat. He could have miscalculated, been overconfident. Everyone makes mistakes; it's not like he had some supernatural rationality power. He wasn't some kind of evil god; just a wizard smarter, more resourceful, and more powerful than most.

And Hermione had left her room and started interacting with people again. She apparently seemed fine to everyone, despite the sudden and inexplicable interest in quidditch. Maybe she'd just been homesick or something all along and spending some time at home had fixed everything. In retrospect, it was possible Harry had been overly paranoid. He had called for Moody to search his office twice, and both times had been false alarms.

Moody had told Harry about a potion called Bahl's Stupifaction, which produced a confundus-like effect causing people to make stupid decisions for an extended time, typically resulting in self-sabotage of whatever they were attempting. It had been a long shot, but apparently there had been a chance that Voldemort had been exposed to it while performing his resurrection ritual. Which made his defeat more believable. Bahl's Stupifaction- Harry's current hypothesis was that it was like the opposite of liquid luck and both potions somehow used information from the future; one potion caused people to make decisions which turned out to be optimal and the other caused maximally suboptimal decisions. He really needed to find some liquid luck to test. For someone smart, it could be an instant victory condition; it could allow one to skip over hours of trial and error to produce workable solutions to any number of problems. He'd have to find a subtle way to discuss it with Lockhart. Or maybe just let Moody read his mind.

Chapter 18: Recklessness, Pt 1

Author's note: It's probably obvious that I've been having difficulty getting motivated to write recently, so I'm putting this story onto a steep glide path for the ending. I may come back and add in scenes or details or clean it up later, but for now, I'm sure everyone would prefer a story with an ending to yet another abandoned story, forever partially finished.

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world and, though Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors, work on the Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities and the temporary hospital in Azkaban tower has been shut down after being compromised by Bellatrix. Many aurors were killed or fatally injured and are in transfiguration-based stasis awaiting treatment.

Moody detected evidence of horcrux possession on Hermione and probably on Sprout. Draco and other students demonstrated unusual behavior and were later found to have been memory charmed. Harry thought of potential countermeasures Voldemort could have used against parseltongue and obliviation and suspects that Voldemort survived, that his plan had been to pretend to lose while preparing a powerful and immortal host for himself who Harry would trust implicitly (and explicitly, given the unbreakable vow). Unfortunately, that same vow prevented Harry from sharing his suspicions, until Moody revealed that he'd been thinking similar things. Thus far, efforts to locate a horcrux at Hogwarts have been unsuccessful.

Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. And obviously plotting something.

Harry has a relatively long list of things he intends to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, time-turner paradoxes, magic-technology interactions, and rescuing Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem or whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped, so he has focused more strongly on learning arithmancy, which involves putting spells together to achieve novel functions.

A girl skipped through the hallways, barefoot, wearing robes several sizes too large, and apparently also oblivious to the rest of her surroundings.

"Lovegood! Wow, did you pick the wrong hallway. Do you have any idea how many of our families you've slandered with that disgusting thing you call a newspaper? Do you have any idea what we're going to do to you?"

A brief moment of eye contact before her eyes unfocused again. "You're going to give me ice cream I assume. Why else would I bring you here?"

A confused pause. "Only if 'ice cream' is what 'pain' is called in that bag of retarded cats you use for a brain."

"No, thank you; that would be unpleasant. Ooh- a ride on a winged horse would be more pleasant than ice cream. That's what you should do before you disappear."

"We're not going anywhere, Loony. We're going to give you a brief introduction to reality."

She laughed, "Reality! This is a dream, silly. I'm sorry I have to tell you this, but when I wake up in a few hours, you'll cease to exist. Unless my subconscious decides you deserve to get resurrected, I guess. But so far, you're wasting your existence. If I know my dreams, Professor Lockhart and Headmaster Dumbledore are about to show up, wearing orange and pink robes, and they'll turn you guys into winged horses so we can fly around until breakfast time."

There was a longer pause. Then they raised their wands-

Only to quickly hide them as Lockhart stepped out of an intersecting hallway, wearing orange robes with pink horses on them. "Hello, Luna. I love winged horses. How are you tonight?"

Luna smiled. The others slowly backed away.

Then startled as Dumbledore walked up behind them, wearing pink robes with orange horses on them and added, "I also think there are far too few winged horses here today. What do you think, Luna?"

The others ran past her before she could answer. Lockhart and Dumbledore just shook their heads, turned and walked away.

The girl's skin stretched and twisted for a few seconds, transforming into Tonks. "Okay, Harry, NOW will you explain this? And WHY can't I just blast them with something unpleasant? And how did you get Professor Lockhart to play along?"

Harry pulled back his invisibility cloak. "Luna's great, but seriously, who would believe she was secretly a battle magic prodigy? It's much more believable that she'd be able to accidental-magic the entire universe into something weirder any time it started to make too much sense. You could probably convince a lot of people that that has already happened; imagine how many Quibbler headlines it would explain."

Dumbledore and Lockhart returned. They turned to each other and simultaneously cast, "Polyfluis reverso."

Fred and George smiled and turned toward Harry. George said, "That was awesome."

Fred added, "What other pranks do you have planned?"

Harry replied, "Nothing at the moment. But don't worry, I'll let you know."

"And before we forget again, our dad wants to talk to you about muggle stuff."

"He was going to send you an owl."

"Yeah, I got it the other day. It's on my list."

The Auror had fallen to the ground, one knee and one hand supporting himself as the other hand gestured frantically and his mouth shouted desperate words, the few incantations that Harry recognized were all shield spells, as a flock of shadows spun around the Auror like a whirlwind of razors.

And Harry saw Professor Quirrell's Polyjuiced form deliberately point his wand at where the Auror kneeled and fought the last moments of his battle.

"Surrender," said the gravelly voice.

The Auror spat something unspeakable.

In that case," said the voice, Avada -"

Time seemed to move very slowly, like there was time to hear the individual syllables, Ke, and Da, and Vra, time to watch the Auror starting to throw himself desperately aside; and even though it was all happening so slowly, somehow there wasn't time to do anything, no time for Harry to open his lips and scream NO, no time to move, maybe even not any time to think.

Then there was pain.

Harry groaned and picked up his watch. He sighed and put it back. Another dream about Voldemort, with Dementors and Death nearby. His compulsion to provide healing with the Philosopher's Stone and inability to act on it would naturally monopolize his subconscious. He decided he would have to begin studying warding so he could help rework Hogwarts' wards himself. He then felt around the bed for his wand, pointed it at himself and whispered, 'somnium'.

"There are still physical anchors for your immortality," Harry said aloud. "It resembles the old horcrux spell by that much, which is another reason you still call them horcruxes. If I'm wrong, you can always deny it in Parseltongue."

Professor Quirrell was smiling evilly. "Your guesss iss right, boy, for all the good it doess you."

"One horcux dropped into an active volcano, weighted so it would sink into the Earth's mantle. One horcrux buried kilometers down, in an anonymous cubic meter of the Earth's crust. One horcrux you dropped into the Mariana Trench. One horcrux floating high in the stratosphere, transparent. Even you don't know where they are, because you Obliviated the exact details from your memory. And the last horcrux is the Pioneer 11 plaque that you snuck into NASA and modified. It's where you get your image of the stars, when you cast the spell of starlight. Fire, earth, water, air, void." Something of a riddle, the Defense Professor had called it, and therefore Harry had remembered it. Something of a Riddle. "Tell me, teacher," Harry hissed, "would desstroying thosse five anchors sslay you? "

"Your ssusspicion iss right, boy. Desstroying thosse five would not render me mortal."

Harry's throat felt a bit dry again. If the spell had no disastrous cost associated with it... "How many anchorss did you make? "

"Would not ordinarily ssay, but iss clear you have already guesssed." The Defense Professor's smile widened. "Ansswer iss that I do not know. Sstopped counting ssomewhere around one hundred and sseven. Ssimply made a habit of it each time I murdered ssomeone in private."

Harry groaned and looked at his watch. Finally, it was breakfast time.

"Excellent technique, Mr. Zabini", Lockhart complimented over the scattered applause. "You should think about trying to get onto a dueling team in a few years. Next, let's have Ms. Bulstrode and...", he glanced at a parchment while quietly commenting, "who hasn't participated in a while... Mr. Potter."

Harry rolled his eyes, "Really?" He glanced toward Milicent, "No offense." He looked back at Lockhart, "Seriously, how hard would it be to start an Elo rating system for this?"

"And who would you prefer to duel?"

"I don't know... Although... we haven't seen you actually do anything this year. That could be illuminating."

Lockhart smiled, "I suppose stunning you would be the fastest way to stop you from disrupting class." He waved Harry to the front right of the class walked to the left.

After they were ready, Harry raised his wand and fired the first shot.

Lockhart spun to his right, the light of the expelliarmus narrowly grazing his robe. As he turned, he pointed his wand backwards and fired a stupify blindly. He smoothly finished the turn facing Harry with his wand raised.

Harry watched the red light fly off to his right, at least 30 degrees off target, smirked, and prepared to fire again. Meanwhile, the spell ricocheted off Lockhart's desk and hit Harry in the side of the head. He dropped.

Lockhart suppressed a grin, "Okay, class, first of all, don't use trick shots like that (unless you become a professional and really want to make a point). In a real fight, it's a good way to get killed. And more importantly, don't make his mistake: never underestimate an opponent."

Hanna raised her hand and asked, "What rule number is that one?"

Lockhart frowned, "I never needed to number that rule; I assumed it was obvious."

Moody grunted approvingly, "It's about time we moved against Lockhart. What's the plan? And what did you catch him doing?"

Harry froze, "I... don't have a good answer for that. It just kind of happened."

Moody scowled, "You attacked a dark wizard with no plan? Now he probably knows we're onto him. It will be that much harder to catch him doing whatever he's doing. Are you getting dumber?"

Harry sighed, "I've had a lot on my mind. And relative to last year, there's also that mind-altering spell I'm under."

Moody retorted, "Are you telling me the world would've ended if you hadn't challenged Lockhart?"

Harry looked down and shook his head.

Moody scoffed and shook his head. McGonagall interjected, "So obviously you must serve detention. Luckily, Professor Lockhart doesn't want to supervise your detention; he said he doesn't have time to deal with you this evening. So I'll let you choose between helping with Potions, History of Magic, or Arithmancy."

Professor Vector shrugged, "I don't get many students serving detention here. A few students come in regularly for extra help with class. I guess do what you can for them. Otherwise, I don't know, organize the closet or study quietly."

Harry nodded in understanding and Vector went into the adjoining office.

Some time later, Percy Weasley entered the classroom.

Harry frowned, "Aren't you doing really well in this class?"

"Yes, and now you know why. So why are you here?"

Harry shrugged, "Detention slash reading an introduction to warding theory. I'm supposed to help students with Arithmancy if I can. Do you want to learn about preparing a site for a basic warding spell?"

"Not really. I remember that you know more advanced things about flying spells. Let's talk about that."

Harry shrugged again, "Okay, I could use a break from this stuff anyway."

"Also, my father is really interested in talking to you about muggle technology and how you've used it along with magic. I think he sent you an owl."

"He did. We scheduled an appointment."

"Tom Riddle!"

Harry froze then drew his wand slowly. He didn't recognize the voices and couldn't see anyone in the hallway. Apparently everyone in this hallway was invisible.

"Tom Harry Potter-Riddle-Evans-Verres!" Simultaneously, a balled-up parchment hit Harry in the back. He dodged and crouched against a wall, pointing his wand in the direction the object had originated. Another small object hit him in the back. Someone could evidently track him despite his invisibility cloak, while he lacked a similar-

Never mind, he'd handled that before. "Luminos maximus", he called, holding up his wand and shutting his eyes while running a short distance down the hall. "Glisseo." He then blindly fired stunners at the sounds of squeaking shoes and hands hitting the floor.

He walked over to the sleeping bodies. "You idiots. Enervate. Enervate. YOU IDIOTS!" Fred and George looked up at him blankly. "You're lucky to be alive. What are you thinking, attacking people in hallways at night while Vo... What are you idiots thinking?"

"We knew you were walking alone at night wearing an invisibility cloak", Fred began as they slowly stood up.

"So it must be safe for us to walk around together and invisible, despite whatever."

"You're still really lucky. I mean, if I'd been someone bad, I could've killed you", Harry replied.

"To be fair, we thought we were in a strong enough position to handle whatever you'd do."

"Especially after we were reminded that you really still can lose a duel."

"This prank looked foolproof on parchment."

"So what's the deal with the Tom Riddle thing?"

"How were you following me? And where... oh. I take it you guys found the map again. So I guess my question is how were you reading it while you were invisible?"

"What map?"

"Wait, what do you mean 'again'?"

"Yeah, you had it last year, then Voldemort took it and obliviated you. How did you get it back anyway?"

George answered, "We found it", while Fred simultaneously exclaimed, "We made it."

Harry scoffed, "You didn't make it. It's part of the Hogwarts security system. Students couldn't make anything like that."

Fred held out the map so Harry could read it, "Yeah, because the Hogwarts founders used the code names 'Mooney', 'Padfoot', 'Prongs', and 'Wormtail'."

George added, "And of course they'd use the password, 'I solemnly swear I'm up to no good', for their security." The map fell open as he finished.

Fred continued, "And don't think you can distract us that easily. What did you do with the real Harry Potter?"

"I...", Harry paused for a moment, then gasped, spun around, and sprinted down the hallway.

"I'll give him 9/10 for foiling the prank..."

"But his exit strategy needs work."

"If he'd used that bright light to cover his escape, it would've been a 10/10."

"Maybe we should go after him?"

"He did seem to think it's unsafe alone out here."

"It's for his own safety, really."

They jogged down the hallway.

Harry had nearly reached the gargoyles when he intercepted McGonagall returning to her office.

"Headmistress McGonagall, do you know who the 'Marauders' are?"

She frowned, then smiled at him, "In retrospect, I'm surprised it's taken you this long to ask."

Harry frowned, "You knew and you didn't bring it up before?"

"I prefer to think about happier times, rather than the endless series of detentions I had to supervise once I figured out who they were."

"Thinking happy thoughts? Over what could be the key to the future of the world!?"

"Wait, what?"

"That there are apparently one or more charms prodigies out there with experience hacking into Hogwarts' wards?"

"Oh. I thought you were asking about your father. Wait, they accessed the wards?"

"There's a map of Hogwarts that Voldemort had last year. It's either powerful enough to track everyone on the grounds or it's linked to the security wards. It's extremely unlikely that students would have been able to produce something with that kind of reach and have it last this long, so I'm betting on the latter. And what did you say about my father?"

"James Potter was one of the Marauders. He went by 'Prongs', named for his stag animagus form. The others were Remus Lupin, Peter Pettigrew, and Sirius Black."

Harry frowned, "It seems overly improbable that I've heard about all these people before."

McGonagall shrugged, "As children, they were talented and motivated to learn magic, though they often used what they knew in ways that got them in trouble. So naturally, as adults, they were knowledgeable and capable and not predisposed to keeping their heads down when things got bad."

Harry nodded, "Fair enough."

McGonagall suddenly spun to her left, wand raised, and cast, "Homenum Revelio."

Fred and George glanced at each other. George observed, "We're zero for two at this."

Fred continued, "We should probably stop until we learn the real disillusionment spell rather than the beginner version."

George nodded then turned to Harry, "So you're a junior marauder..."

Fred continued, "Yeah, that explains so much."

McGonagall began to nod, then stopped herself. Then she waved her wand and the map flew out of Fred's robes and into her hand. She added dryly, "If the two of you have nowhere else to be, I'm sure I can make the time to discuss where you obtained this and go over all of the jobs around this school that could benefit from your talents." They retreated quickly.

McGonagall frowned after casting a series of charms on the map, "Are you sure this does anything?"

Harry took that map and pronounced, "I solemnly swear I'm up to no good". The map opened and Harry handed it back to McGonagall. "Anyway, we should give Remus Lupin whatever amount of money it takes for him to consult with the warding specialists. He apparently has a few years head start on them, so he may be able to speed up progress on the hospital project."

"I'll contact him first thing tomorrow." She was distracted by movement on the map, "What is going on in the Forbidden Forrest? There must be forty people out there."

"That's odd. We should check it out."

"You go to bed. I'll check."

There was a scream. McGonagall started jogging. From the last time she checked the map, she estimated that she was relatively close to the group. Possibly not too late to help whoever was in trouble.

Thirty seconds later, she could see occasional red flashes through the trees. A few seconds later she could hear voices. She couldn't understand the words, but heard occasional laughter.

Then there was another scream. Then whole area lit up with red light.

"... more observant. I cannot overstate the importance of situational awareness." She recognized the voice as Lockhart. He continued, "Now you'll have to excuse me for a moment." He emerged from the crowd, walking toward McGonagall. "Good evening, Headmistress. What seems to be the problem?"

"What... is going on here?"

"Well, you asked me to deal with the acromantula infestation. It turned out that there were quite a lot of them. So I did the obvious thing."

"You asked a lot of people to help out?"

"Oh, no. I put up some advertisements, 'Dark Creature Defense Seminar with Gilderoy Lockhart (with book signing to follow)'. And I set the price lower than I'd have preferred to make sure the turnout was high. So I've been teaching everyone how to track and stun acromantulas and some useful tips about the other animals out here."

"This doesn't seem safe at all."

Lockhart flashed a smile, "One moment please." He turned and fired a stupify, hitting an acromantula in midair. After firing the stunner, he cast a hover charm and pulled a woman aside just before it landed where she'd been standing. She screamed. Dozens of stunning charms hit the already unconscious spider as the others turned and saw it.

Lockhart called out, "Acromantulas also sometimes ambush prey rather than waiting for it to become trapped in their webs. They often drop from tree branches onto their prey, so it's important to stay aware of what's above you." He turned back to McGonagall, "They're obviously not the best at this, but I've got everything under control. Also, I negotiated with the Ministry of Travel for bulk rate portkeys. I'm getting a 90% discount for travel between midnight and four AM with a minimum purchase of 20 portkeys. So I'll have the spiders on their way to Brazil in a few hours... I assume Hogwarts will be reimbursing the other 10%. It is a facility maintenance expense, after all."

McGonagall sighed, "I'm too tired to deal with this. We'll talk about it tomorrow."

Chapter 20: Investigation

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world and, though Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors, work on the Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities and the temporary hospital in Azkaban tower has been shut down after being compromised by Bellatrix. Many aurors were killed or fatally injured and are in transfiguration-based stasis awaiting treatment.

Moody detected evidence of horcrux possession on Hermione and probably on Sprout. Draco and other students demonstrated unusual behavior and were later found to have been memory charmed. Harry thought of potential countermeasures Voldemort could have used against parseltongue and obliviation and suspects that Voldemort survived, that his plan had been to pretend to lose while preparing a powerful and immortal host for himself who Harry would trust implicitly (and explicitly, given the unbreakable vow). Unfortunately, that same vow prevented Harry from sharing his suspicions, until Moody revealed that he'd been thinking similar things. Thus far, efforts to locate a horcrux at Hogwarts have been unsuccessful.

Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. And obviously plotting something.

Harry has a relatively long list of things he intends to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, time-turner paradoxes, magic-technology interactions, and rescuing Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem or whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped, so he has focused more strongly on learning arithmancy, which involves putting spells together to achieve novel functions.

Public opinion is divided on Harry's recent use of Voldemort role-play to frighten students, and a group of Hufflepuffs are out after curfew...

"You all looked at the right person for entirely the wrong reasons. After I heard rumors of one Ravenclaw facing down five older Slytherins, I came to the conclusion that Harry Potter would be my most dangerous student. You're thinking that I've come up with a wrong answer, aren't you, Mr. Potter? You will learn to expect better of me. Mr. Potter, all things have their accustomed uses. Give me ten unaccustomed uses of objects in this room for combat!"

For a moment Harry was rendered speechless by the sheer, raw shock of having been understood.

And then the ideas started to pour out.

"There are desks which are heavy enough to be fatal if dropped from a great height. There are chairs with metal legs that could impale someone if driven hard enough. The air in this classroom would be deadly by its absence, since people die in vacuum, and it can serve as a carrier for poison gases. The floor can be removed to create a spike pit to fall into, the ceiling can be collapsed on someone, the walls can serve as raw material for Transfiguration into any number of deadly things - knives, say."

"That's six. But surely you're scraping the bottom of the barrel now?"

"I haven't even started! Just look at all the people! Having a Gryffindor attack the enemy is an ordinary use, of course but their blood can also be used to drown someone. Ravenclaws are known for their brains, but their internal organs could be sold on the black market for enough money to hire an assassin. Slytherins aren't just useful as assassins, they can also be thrown at sufficient velocity to crush an enemy. And Hufflepuffs, in addition to being hard workers, also contain bones that can be removed, sharpened, and used to stab someone."

By now the rest of the class was staring at Harry in some horror. Even the Slytherins looked shocked.

"That's ten, though I'm being generous in counting the Ravenclaw one. Now, for extra credit, one Quirrell point for each use of objects in this room which you have not yet named." Professor Quirrell favored Harry with a companionable smile. "The rest of your class thinks you are in trouble now, since you've named everything except the targets and you have no idea what may be done with those."

"Bah! I've named all the people, but not my robes, which can be used to suffocate an enemy if wrapped around their head enough times, or Hermione Granger's robes, which can be torn into strips and tied into a rope and used to hang someone, or Draco Malfoy's robes, which can be used to start a fire. My wand can be pushed into an enemy's brain through their eye socket" and someone made a horrified, strangling sound. "My wristwatch could suffocate someone if jammed down their throat -"

"Five points, and enough."

"Hmph," Harry said. "Ten Quirrell points to one House point, right? You should have let me keep going until I'd won the House Cup, I haven't even started yet on the unaccustomed uses of everything I've got in my pockets" or the mokeskin pouch itself and he couldn't talk about the Time-Turner or the invisibility cloak but there had to be something he could say about those red spheres...

"Enough, Mr. Potter. Well, do you all think you understand what makes Mr. Potter the most dangerous student in the classroom? Say it out loud, please. Terry Boot, what makes your dorm-mate dangerous?"

"Ah... um... he's creative?"

"Wrong! " bellowed Professor Quirrell, and his fist came down sharply on his desk with an amplified sound that made everyone jump. "All of Mr. Potter's ideas were worse than useless!"

Harry started in surprise.

"Remove the floor to create a spike trap? Ridiculous! In combat you do not have that sort of preparation time and if you did there would be a hundred better uses! Transfigure material from the walls? Mr. Potter cannot perform Transfiguration! Mr. Potter had exactly one idea which he could use immediately, right now, without extensive preparation or a cooperative enemy or magic he does not know. That idea was to jam his wand through his enemy's eye socket. Which would be more likely to break his wand than kill his opponent! In short, Mr. Potter, I'm afraid that your proposals were uniformly awful."

"What?" Harry said indignantly. "You asked for unusual ideas, not practical ones! I was thinking outside the box! How would you use something in this classroom to kill someone?"

Professor Quirrell's expression was disapproving, but there were smile crinkles around his eyes. "Mr. Potter, I never said you were to kill. There is a time and a place for taking your enemy alive, and inside a Hogwarts classroom is usually one of those places. But to answer your question, hit them on the neck with the edge of a chair."

There was some laughter from the Slytherins, but they were laughing with Harry, not at him.

Everyone else was looking rather horrified.

"But Mr. Potter has now demonstrated why he is the most dangerous student in the classroom. I asked for unaccustomed uses of items in this room for combat. Mr. Potter could have suggested using a desk to block a curse, or using a chair to trip an oncoming enemy, or wrapping cloth around his arm to create an improvised shield. Instead, every single use that Mr. Potter named was offensive rather than defensive, and either fatal or potentially fatal."

What? Wait, that couldn't be true... Harry had a sudden sense of vertigo as he tried to remember what exactly he'd suggested, surely there had to be a counterexample...

"And that," Professor Quirrell said, "is why Mr. Potter's ideas were so strange and useless - because he had to reach far into the impractical in order to meet his standard of killing the enemy. To him, any idea which fell short of that was not worth considering. This reflects a quality that we might call intent to kill. I have it. Harry Potter has it, which is how he could stare down five older Slytherins. Draco Malfoy does not have it, not yet. Mr. Malfoy would hardly shrink from talk of ordinary murder, but even he was shocked - yes you were Mr. Malfoy, I was watching your face - when Mr. Potter described how to use his classmates' bodies as raw material. There are censors inside your mind which make you flinch away from thoughts like that. Mr. Potter thinks purely of killing the enemy, he will grasp at any means to do so, he does not flinch, his censors are off. Even though his youthful genius is so undisciplined and impractical as to be useless, his intent to kill makes Harry Potter the Most Dangerous Student in the Classroom. One final point to him - no, let us make that a point to Ravenclaw - for this indispensable requisite of a true fighting wizard."

"Mr. Potter..."

Harry opened his eyes and saw a glowing white cat floating above him.

"... I'm in the second floor corridor nearest the Hufflepuff common room, about halfway to the History of Magic classroom. There's something here you should see."

Harry glanced at his watch: 2:30AM. That couldn't be a good sign.

Harry quickly got dressed and headed out. The walk gave him ample time to relive the dream. He could only conclude that despite Voldemort and Bellatrix on the loose, his subconscious had found the time to obsess about his own potential as a threat. That couldn't be a good sign.

Some time earlier...

"Minerva! Headmistress McGonagall! Please wake up, it's an emergency! Come to the Hufflepuff common room as soon as possible."

She opened her eyes in time to see Sprout's patronus fade away.

A few minutes later, as she neared the room, Sprout called out "This way", and started climbing a staircase. McGonagall rushed to catch up.

"Six of my students are missing", Sprout announced. "As soon as I was informed, I asked the prefects to help me start a search. We haven't found them, but you need to see this."

Written on the wall in large red letters was the message: "The Chamber of Secrets has been opened. Enemies of the heir, beware."

Even earlier...

Cedric cast a light from the end of his wand but kept it horizontal, ready to cast a curse if necessary, as he strode forward.

The other students held their breath and tried not to make a sound.

Cedric stopped. The door to the classroom on his left was wide open. He listened for a few seconds, then took a step into the room, quickly taking a dueling stance and sweeping his wand around the room.

He promptly collapsed backwards into the hallway, his eyes open but unfocused.

Most of the others screamed as they felt the magical explosion. Someone ran forward and called out, "He's not breathing!"

Some began to retreat, while others froze in place.

They heard something moving inside the room and instantly fell silent and raised their wands.

McGonagall sighed, "Keep searching for the students. I'll call Filius to help me find out what caused this."

Sprout asked, "I know Albus is officially missing, but I don't suppose there's any chance you could get him an emergency message?"

"I suppose there's some possibility he set up a spell to bring him to Hogwarts when he's truly needed, but if there is such a spell or a way that I could trigger it, I don't know of it."

McGonagall then sent her patronus to summon Flitwick, Lockhart, and Harry, and Moody.

Flitwick arrived first, and McGonagall told him about the missing students and message. He began using his wand to scan the text and surrounding area.

Harry overheard part of the explanation while walking down the hall and immediately activated his time-turner.

Moody announced, "I can't believe you called Lockhart before me."

McGonagall turned to see Moody and Harry step around a corner, "He is a professor at this school. And may have something useful to contribute."

"Luckily, Harry called me six hours ago. So I've had twelve hours to investigate."

"Time turners don't work like that."

"I kept going back to the moment after Harry called me and searching in different directions. But it was apparently too late. Both the basilisk and its master were already gone."

"What?"

Harry interrupted, "Let's start at the beginning." He sighed, "They were all dead when I arrived. I don't know for how long, but they were still warm-ish. I called Moody, then six of his time-turned selves appeared and examined the bodies. Then all of the Moodys searched while I cooled the bodies and worked on transfiguring them. I don't know whether they can be revived or how much brain damage they'll have if I do, but I have to try.

"The first Moody arrived maybe ten minutes later and I explained the situation. He scanned the message on the wall, helped me transfigure the rest of the bodies, then time turned back. We've been in the library since then."

Moody explained, "They had no visible injuries. It looked like they'd been hit by killing curses. But you and I have tested the wards that tell you when unforgivables and memory charms are cast. We couldn't test the wards for death or serious injury, and apparently you're not getting those notifications, so we'll have to work on that later. Anyway, we researched other spells that could mimic the effect of a killing curse but would be less likely to be detected."

Harry added, "A basilisk is most likely. I think their eyes emit something like an extremely low powered killing curse in all directions, which can be blocked by essentially anything opaque. So it only kills with a direct hit to someone's central nervous system which, in practice means that someone has to look at its eyes such that the curse hits their retina-"

Moody interrupted, "However it works, looking at basilisk eyes kills, and looks enough like a killing curse."

Harry continued, "Also, it fits with the Heir of Slytherin message because the parselmouth connection. We should probably check Slytherin's Chamber of Secrets."

They both stared at him, Moody asked, "You know where it is?", while McGonagall exclaimed, "Mr. Potter! You promised you'd report that if you found it!"

"It kind of slipped my mind with everything else that happened that night... there was an entrance in the dungeons, but I don't remember where. There's another entrance via a tunnel that opens in the graveyard near Hogsmead. That should be easy enough to find..."

A few hours later, they emerged from the tunnels into a closet in an unused fifth floor classroom.

"That place is a complete maze. We'll never be able to find anything down there."

Harry shrugged, "I'll try to find an optimal maze navigation algorithm and we can try again. Or maybe someone can find a way to modify the map to plot the tunnels; I believe that's what Voldemort was using it for."

Moody warded the entrance so McGonagall would be notified if anyone approached it, and they returned to area near the Hufflepuff room.

On the way, Lockhart intercepted them, smiling brightly.

McGonagall called angrily, "Professor Lockhart, where have you been? We had a situation and couldn't reach you."

"I was out of the castle. It took some time for me to get back."

Moody stared Lockhart down and demanded, "Where exactly have you been for the past 8 hours?"

"Brazil."

McGonagall queried, "The Acromantulas?"

"We could say that I didn't have enough time to transport them all the other day."

Moody continued, "Anyone who can verify?"

"I had the portkeys made a few days ago, and no one was with me when I made the trips, though I suppose there were a few ladies at the bar who'd remember me."

"Names?"

"I didn't exactly take attendance."

"Name of the bar?"

"I could possibly find it again..."

Moody grinned dangerously, "So you have no alibi."

"My contract doesn't say anything about being in Hogwarts castle at night or having my movements restricted in any way. It says I must be present for my classes, offices hours, and any extra-curricular activities I sponsor. And anyway, I was doing my best to avoid the defense position curse."

"Oh?"

"I've read up on what's happened to previous professors. Many times their contracts were not renewed due to incompetence, sometimes resulting in their own injury or injured students. Of course I don't have anything to worry about there." He smiled at Moody, who scowled back. "And I don't think I have to tell you about the scandals many of the others get into. Therefore, I've precommitted to spending as much time as possible outside the castle. Can't get into trouble here if I'm there, can I?" He stumbled, caught himself, and attempted to lean against the wall in a casual-looking pose.

McGonagall frowned, "Are you drunk?"

"Well, I didn't think it was a good idea to apparate on the way here if that's what you mean." He made a quick exit, which was, of course, totally dignified and not influenced at all by the angry look McGonagall was giving him.

Harry found himself confused. He'd ignored most of the conversation, having found the topic boring, but something about what Lockhart had said felt significant. He'd need to keep thinking about it. But dealing with this year's defense professor wasn't particularly high on his priority list. Hopefully Headmistress McGonagall could handle it.

Lockhart shook his head as he walked back to his room, thinking about how that conversation could have gone better. He stopped when he noticed a student whose name he couldn't recall waiting outside his room. "It's after curfew. You should be in your house's common area or room or something."

"I needed to talk to you. I... recently acquired this artifact that I believe may be valuable and historic. Do you have a way to find out if it's real?"

Lockhart continued walking forward, "Oh. That is interesting. Let me see that..."

Moody practically spat, "How can you let that man work here?"

McGonagall shrugged, "He may be a poor role model, but we need defense professors, and he was the only competent candidate who applied for this year." She glanced at Harry, "and at least he wasn't the one pretending to be Voldemort at dinner."

Moody turned to Harry and narrowed his eyes, "I swear you've gotten stupider since last year. I'm almost not even surprised after you picked a pointless fight with Lockhart and hid your suspicions about Hermione."

McGonagall looked confused, "What about Hermione?"

Moody grunted, "That she's possessed by Voldie." McGonagall gasped. Moody turned back to Harry, "Actually, it bothers me less that you tried to hide information that you considered sensitive than that you thought I wouldn't figure that out for myself. It's like you don't even know me." He turned back to McGonagall, "Yeah, that's why we haven't been inviting her to our meetings like we were earlier this year."

McGonagall frowned, "I had been wondering about that. But... really?"

Harry frowned and responded to Moody, "It's more likely that you only notice whether people exceed or fall short of your expectations and that your expectations for me have significantly increased since last year. If your expectations are tuned accurately, I should surprise you in positive and negative ways about equally often."

Moody looked at Harry thoughtfully for a moment, "Well, you're right about one thing: my expectations for first year students can only increase." He leveled his wand at Harry, "anyway... finite incantatem... polyfluis reverso... nullus confundio." He continued casting, checking for horcrux possession and other things Harry didn't recognize.

Harry rolled his eyes, "I'm me and I'm not under any spells. I think I would've known. And I don't feel any different now."

"No, you wouldn't know. You'd probably be the last to notice. And now I suspect you don't even have a plan for what to do next."

Harry sighed, "I'll have to think about it."

Harry sat in his office, thinking. He was reasonably certain Moody was wrong, but decided it would still be prudent to check his office for anything suspicious.

He emptied the contents of his pouch onto the desk. He lifted his wand and cast a confundus detection charm at one of his textbooks. Negative result. He moved on to another and continued.

A moment later he stopped and stepped back, looking around at the shelves and back at the pile of objects on the desk. "This is going to take forever. I need a faster way to do this."

"Come in, Harry", Flitwick called.

"Hello, professor. I'm trying to charm something to detect confundus charms, to turn red if it touches something charmed with a confundus and green if it touches something without a confundus."

Flitwick frowned, "That's a relatively straightforward application of arithmancy. I'm surprised you're having an issue."

Harry sighed and handed him a thin wooden rod, resembling a two-foot long wand, "That seems to be a popular opinion recently."

"What?"

"Never mind."

Flitwick inspected the wand with his own, "The charms on this will do exactly what you described."

Harry nodded and opened his pouch, placing his arithmancy textbook, a can of comed-tea, a notebook, and the dueling target on a desk. "Then try it on these things and compare the results with your own detection charm."

Flitwick briefly frowned, then stepped forward. "There's a confundus on the comed-tea, as we already knew. Have you been playing with that again? The other objects are clean." He then touched the objects with the detection-wand. "Green, red, green, and... red? Oh. That's odd."

"Yeah. That's the result I've been getting. Do you have any idea what could do that?"

Flitwick silently cast a series of analytic charms at the dueling target, then at the detection-wand. "Has anything else produced that result?"

"No, it hasn't turned red for anything but the comed-tea and dueling target."

"Well, this is exciting! No one's found a problem with the standard analytic charms in centuries. We should figure out exactly what triggers the false result with the analytic charm on a stick. Lots of people will be interested to know about it. Especially if we can find a case where it also affects the charm when cast directly."

"I have another hypothesis. Can you put the other confundus analysis charms on that rod? To show what a confundus is doing?"

"It's more complicated than that..."

"Can you check whether there's a confundus that does one specific thing?"

"Yes. What are you thinking?"

"Check if there's a confundus that causes people who cast a confundus detection charm to think the result was negative."

Flitwick stared at Harry for a moment, "That's an interesting idea." He silently cast spells at the detection-wand for a moment, then touched the dueling target. The rod turned purple. Flitwick looked up at Harry, surprised, "You were right!"

Harry nodded, "I'm going to call Headmistress McGonagall. She needs to see this."

"It's an interesting use of arithmancy, but I don't know that it's worth her time..."

"Trust me, she'll want to see this. I'll have her meet us in the defense classroom." He walked out, briefly turning back to make sure Flitwick was following.

A short time later, Harry and Flitwick met McGonagall and Moody in the defense classroom.

Moody noted, "It looks like Lockhart's already left for the day."

McGonagall asked, "What is it Professor Flitwick, Mr. Potter?"

Flitwick looked over to Harry. Harry began, "This dueling target has a confundus charm on it-"

Moody quickly cast an analytic charm and interrupted, "No, it doesn't."

"One effect of the charm is to fool people who cast analytic charms at it into thinking there's no confundus."

Moody nodded slowly.

McGonagall said, "That's... disturbing. Anything could be charmed and no one would ever know."

Flitwick elaborated, "You can find them if you charm an object to do the detection for you."

Moody looked around, then turned back toward Harry, "A nearly undetectable curse on a dueling target. So this it then?"

Harry nodded, "I'm pretty sure. I suspect the other targets are the same, but we should check. They're held in the ceiling somehow."

Flitwick gestured his wand at the ceiling, opening it. He cast a series of spells at a roll of parchment. The parchment exploded into shreds which flew out in all directions, collided with every object in the room, then reflected back and formed a scale model of the room, mostly green, but with red spheres at the ceiling. "All of the dueling targets, and only the dueling targets", Flitwick concluded.

Harry commented, "I'm going to need the details on how you did that. Some of those spells should help with another project-"

McGonagall interrupted, "What exactly does this mean?"

Moody turned to McGonagall, "Where did those targets come from?"

"I... don't recall. They still have internal magic, so they can't be more than a few years old."

Harry shook his head, "My previous research hinted that they may be able to absorb magic from Hogwarts."

Moody chuckled softly, "This is definitely it."

McGonagall repeated, "What do you mean?"

Moody smirked, "no matter how you change classrooms or revise syllibi or rename classes, someone's going to teach dueling or defense skills in some form. And that person's classroom is stocked with dueling targets. Apparently not regular dueling targets, but mysterious confundus-charmed dueling targets that no one remembers ordering. And let me guess, Harry- you've been carrying one of them around all year- for some kind of research?"

Harry looked down and nodded.

Moody chuckled again, "Well, I'm taking credit for ending the Hogwarts defense curse."

McGonagall and Flitwick exchanged a surprised glance. Harry just nodded again.

Moody elaborated, "I cast a confundus breaking charm on Harry and a few hours later he's discovered a decades-old confundus curse that Dumbledore couldn't solve. I'm taking credit."

Harry sighed, "Yeah, all things considered, I really should have seen this coming earlier. The way the defense curse reliably results in the dismissal of every professor within the year has similarities to the way comed-tea reliably results in-"

McGonagall interrupted, "So how do we break the curse? Is there a way to remove the protective confundus to see what else it's doing?"

Moody replied, "I'd guess it's lowering people's inhibitions until they do dumb things. That would explain why your defense professors end their careers in diverse ways that were consistent enough with their personalities that no one was ever totally sure the curse existed. And I don't think we should break it until after we get Voldemort out or he might cast something harder to detect. And I don't think we should tell Lockhart, or anyone else about it."

McGonagall scowled, "I know you don't like Lockhart, but you're asking me to allow a teacher to get hurt. Or worse, hurt students."

"We can regularly cast nullio cunfundus at him. He'll be fine. And your students are exactly as safe as they were the last time I told you to fire Lockhart; nothing has changed. Anyway, in the mean time, we should check you office and Harry's office for anything else like this."

Sometime later, two additional confunded objects were discovered, in the Headmistress' office. One was apparently a section of the wall that was difficult to look at directly but otherwise seemed unremarkable.

Moody closed his human eye, pointed his wand in the appropriate direction and cast nullio confundus about twenty times at slightly different points. He announced, "I got it!" He then canceled a disillusionment spell and a small piece of parchment became visible, still stuck to the wall. He walked over and cast a series of analytic charms, then set it on fire. After it burned completely and he had vanished the ashes, he informed the others, "It was an espionage device. Transmits images and sound somewhere else. It was a good one too, no way to trace who was watching, as if we didn't already know. Apparently he had to use different way to spy on us after we stopped inviting the girl to meetings."

The other confunded object was a small fiddly thing with golden wibblers.

Moody frowned, "Do you remember where that came from?"

"Albus made it."

Harry laughed softly. When the others looked at him, he quickly explained, "First, it amuses me that Dumbledore had known about this effect, but used it as a prank and apparently never considered weaponizing it. And second, confunding an object to influence your opponents into defeating themselves is certainly an unusual use of an object in combat. It's certainly something I didn't know could be done with a dueling target last year."

Moody stared at Harry for a moment, "Do you have a workable plan to get Voldie yet?"

"I have... most of a plan. I think we should execute after dinner. I think we'll need lots of aurors and at least one person who still has 6 hours on their time turner for today. And Bones should probably be here too; I'm sure she wants to know what's going on. Let's meet back here at 11 to discuss details, right now I'm starving."

As Hermione walked down the hallway to the Great Hall for breakfast, someone called her name. She turned to see Ginny approaching.

"Hermione, I could really use your help with something if you have a minute..."

Hermione paused for a beat, then put on a friendly smile and replied, "Sure Ginny, what do you need?"

Chapter 21: Hunting Dark Lords

Harry was slowly picking at the remains of his breakfast when Merry Tavington handed him an envelope and quickly walked away. He absentmindedly opened it and began reading, "Potter, meet me at 8:30 in previous meeting location. DM". Harry sighed.

"Good morning, Harry." Hermione sat down next to him.

"Morning", Harry replied.

"Harry, do you know anything about the rumors going around?"

"Rumors?"

"About missing Hufflepuffs? About the Chamber of Secrets?"

"That sounds bad. What are people saying?"

"People say lots of things. I was hoping you knew something more solid. You are the heir of Slytherin, after all. Don't you know something about the Chamber?"

Harry frowned, "I don't know anything about the Chamber that you don't already know."

Hermione's eyes narrowed, "Why aren't you more curious? Salazar left a room for his descendants. There must be something really important there."

Harry stared at her for a moment, then replied, "Well, there aren't many things that last for centuries. Odds are there's nothing of value left down there."

Hermione shrugged, "So what are you working on today?"

"Oh, just the usual."

"You think you could make that a little more vague?"

"Secret meeting, class, homework, secret meeting, lunch, class, secret project, class, dinner, secret project. You know, the usual."

"Whatever." She got up and walked away.

After a few minutes, Harry got up and went to his secret meeting with Draco.

"Potter."

"Malfoy. I guess you're talking to me again."

"This is important, Potter. Are you sure you weren't followed?"

Harry closed the door, and cast 15 privacy spells, "It's as secure as I can make it in the castle without asking someone else for help."

"I guess that will have to be good enough... I shouldn't have to tell you this, but there's something wrong with Hermione."

"What have you noticed?"

Draco groaned, "Have you seriously noticed nothing? What have you been doing?"

"I have my suspicions, but your observations might provide critical information."

"She's been pretty inconspicuous all year (which is odd by itself but not my problem), then first thing this morning, she tries to interrogate me about father's death. It was almost like a Weasley prank, except even more classless than their usual. And I heard she was asking the Hufflepuffs questions about missing students."

"So you first noticed her acting unusual today?"

"You heard what I said. Now stop pretending you don't know anything."

Harry sighed, "She was asking me about the Chamber of Secrets this morning. But I don't know what she's trying to do."

"That's... not a bad question. You are the Heir of Slytherin. What do you know about the Chamber?"

"Draco-"

"And we've never had a chance to talk about last year. We both know the story you told everyone at the quidditch stadium wasn't the whole truth. What do you really know about that?" After a pause, Draco added, "And that implies that you know something about the missing students, because this is all clearly connected somehow."

"Draco... I'm pretty sure there's nothing I can say now that you'll believe, so I'm just going to go."

Harry quietly said, "I should have thought of this earlier, but the map will show... whoever... is possessed by Voldemort as 'Tom Riddle'. We can use it to track him and confirm who his host is."

McGonagall wordlessly retrieved the map and opened it on the table.

Moody questioned, "Are you sure he can't fool it?"

Harry shrugged, "I can't be sure, but it's not confunded and it can see through polyjuice potion, disillusionment, and even my invisibility cloak."

Bones replied, "This is... good. We can use the map and find him right now. But what then? I assume he'll jump bodies as soon as he knows we know, and then we'll have to start over. And then what?"

Moody nodded, "I have some good aurors on stand-by. We'll have to take him down quickly. But it's Voldemort so we'll have to be prepared for everything."

Harry continued, "The core of my plan is for someone to time-turn back with information on Voldemort's location when he's alone. So we can guarantee that the aurors will be there in time (possibly even before Voldemort arrives) and that no students will be around. The details will be more complicated; for one, we have to assume Voldemort has a time-turner. So we'll need anti-time wards in place in addition to anti-apparition, anti-portkey wards and something to detect disillusioned or polyjuiced people or animagi, etc."

McGonagall replied, "With Mr. Lupin's help, the warding specialists are reportedly making progress, but I don't believe they can do something as complicated as anti-time warding yet."

Harry sighed, "Okay, we can fake that: in addition to information on Voldemort's location, someone brings some innocuous information from six hours ahead and announces it in the Great Hall at dinner, so no one in the room will be able to time turn for an hour. We'll need a location for Voldemort during that hour, but you can order an early curfew to get the students out of the way and send aurors straight to him."

McGonagall groaned softly, "I don't like plans involving time-turners. What if we get information about when and where 'Tom Riddle' is alone, gather at that place and time, and find that we only went there because you were there... because we got a message that you were there... I hate time-turners."

Moody scoffed, "That's easy enough. Harry, you're not hunting Voldemort. Either stay in a a crowded place or inform us of where you're going. And we won't plan a raid on your office or one of your classrooms."

Bones suggested, "If Trelawney makes the announcements, he probably won't dare not listen and it won't be as suspicious if the message doesn't make sense. But how many aurors are required for their combined power to match Voldemort? We're not talking about arresting a dangerous wizard so much as waging a small war."

Harry groaned and lowered his head into his hands mumbling, "It's not about power, it's about efficiency."

Moody stared at Harry, "I heard him say something like that once. We thought it was just a taunt. But you know what it means."

Harry answered slowly, "There's... Voldemort clearly knows some Interdicted spells that have been lost to everyone else. But there's a pattern in the way he fights... I've... heard about multiple instances where someone cast a spell at him- standard things that most wizards could shield against- but he'd neutralize them... somehow... that definitely didn't use a shield."

Harry paused for few seconds then continued, "I think Voldemort can absorb magic from spells, similar to the way his dueling targets can absorb magic. It doesn't matter if one person casts a stunner at him or if 40 people cast stunners at him, the spells will fizzle out in mid-air. I believe he can drain shields the same way... He might even be able to directly drain people's magical reserves until they pass out for a moment."

Moody nodded, "Something like that wouldn't work on unforgiveables. Or other dark magic."

Bones added, "I doubt you could imperius him. How many killing curses could you cast at him?"

Moody replied, "I think I could kill him at least a few times for friends of mine he's killed. But I can't imagine how he casts so many killing curses at total strangers."

Harry suggested, "I think we need a dementor; that's one of the only things Voldemort won't be able to deal with, so he'll have to abandon his host. We get info from the future about where he is and who he's possessing. Moody and other aurors cast killing curses (they can use the map to determine safe directions so no one else is hit) at Voldemort to back him into a corner. Some muggle explosives might also help. I can mask the dementor with a patronus so he can't sense it and then release it when he's cornered with it."

Moody glanced at Harry, "You aren't going to be there. We have other people who can cast a patronus."

Harry countered, "But with those, people can still sense the dementor. I think it has to be me."

Everyone else responded in the negative.

"Fine. But it is not acceptable to kill Voldemort's host. He's going to survive either way."

The meeting concluded shortly afterwards. As soon as Harry was out of the room, Bones stopped everyone and announced, "I'm authorizing lethal force. Do whatever you need to do, Mad-Eye."

"...as a result, a new curfew is in effect: until further notice, all students will return directly to their common rooms after dinner and remain there until morning. Professors will accompany students to verify that everyone is accounted for." McGonagall finished as the plates disappeared from the tables.

Trelawney's magically amplified voice boomed through the hall, "The location of importance will be 4-K-19 and the roll will be 3."

There was silence for a moment before the hall filled with whispers and the students hesitantly moved toward the exit.

"Yes, we just got the anti-polyjuice and anti-disillusionment wards in place a few hours ago", Lupin reported.

Moody nodded and turned to Lyall.

"He's going to pass through this hallway in 52 minutes", Lyall pointed at a room on the map. "I know it's cutting it close, but he's going to spend most of the next hour in this area where he will be relatively close to students straggling on their way to their dorms. How much other information do you want?"

Moody considered for a second, "Nothing until I specifically ask. We're already breaking normal protocol by deploying before you collected your intelligence. We're setting ourselves up for nasty time-turner side effects if we know too much. Wait, does anyone else other than my team walk through that hallway while my team is there?"

"Yes, Professor Lockhart enters the area a-"

"That's enough. Okay, no one kill Lockhart. Unless he gives you a good reason. Or a half-decent reason... So let's get the dementor in place back here, put the C4 here and here, the sniper nest here, and everyone else in here. Remember, I want the C4 hidden behind the statues, not magically concealed and, Lupin, I want fidelius charms around the sniper, the other aurors, and around the dementor."

"I can't set up three fidelius charms in an hour. Pick one."

Moody sighed, "Fine. You need a rectangle, right? Can you put two of the ward anchors in this room, one down the hallway here, and one in this room?"

"That should be fine."

"Okay, the sniper nest will be just inside of the hallway ward anchor and that will also cover most of these two rooms. Aurors will hide in this one, and the dementor team in the other. To summarize one final time, when Voldie's host crosses this line, trigger the C4. I want you twelve at this doorway, three prone, three kneeling behind them, three standing behind them, and three for backup. Your goal is to keep Voldie on the defensive after he ducks into the opposing room for cover from the blast. If you're not in the right state of mind to cast a killing curse, get out of the way so someone else can take your place. Unless the shooting has already started- in that case, switch to the cruciatus. Once he's pinned down, you three release your patroni and order the dementor in there. I'll follow up with fiendfyre. If Voldie turns back or goes anywhere besides this room, I want a headshot. And then empty the magazine. If you here a shot, release the dementor immediately. And this wall will be charmed so you can target killing curses through it if necessary. Any questions about what we're going to do?... Then what are you all waiting for? Move, move, move!"

The crowd of students had thinned out somewhat as they approached Ravenclaw Tower, as students from other houses had followed other paths back to their own common rooms. But the whole crowd still came to an instant stop when the students in front suddenly stopped walking.

While the other students were attempting to figure out what was going through a loud variant of the telephone game, Harry levitated above their heads and flew forward.

He stopped just as suddenly as the others had. Written in large red letters, possibly blood: "Their skeletons will lie in the Chamber forever".

Harry sped back over the crowd, headed for the fifth floor entrance they had found that morning.

A voice cut through the din, "Harry..."

"Sorry, Luna. I'm pretty busy at the moment."

"You're looking for something? Or someone?"

Harry stopped. "Yes. There's supposed to be a secret room in the castle-"

"You mean the Chamber of Secrets? That's where Ginny took Hermione."

"What?"

"Ginny took Hermione to the Chamber of Secrets."

"Where?"

"An entrance on the first floor girls bathroom, check the sink. Then straight down the hallway, first opening on the left."

"Thanks Luna, I owe you."

Time had slowed to a crawl.

"All units report", Moody whispered into his mirror for about the fifth time.

"Front line ready."

"Dementor team ready."

"Sniper nest ready... wait, I've got movement... It's Lockhart, approaching from downrange."

Moody growled, "All teams stand by." He leaned out the door and used a hover charm to pull Lockhart down the hallway and into the room.

After recovering his balance, Lockhart asked, "What's all this then?"

"Shut up, stand over there, don't move, and most importantly, shut up."

"You know I could help with whatev-"

"What did I just say?"

Lockhart stepped back and made a series of hand gestures indicating acceptance.

"All units report", Moody whispered.

"Front line ready."

"Dementor team ready."

"Sniper nest ready."

A few minutes passed.

"I've got movement... one suspect, cloaked and hooded."

Everyone tensed, preparing for battle.

"About ten seconds at current speed."

...

"C4 in three seconds... two... one..."

They had all applied silencing charms in preparation, but the sound that got through was still impressive. The figure managed to get a partial shield behind itself soon enough to survive the shrapnel and ducked into the room to its left.

The hallway between the rooms lit up with flashes of green light for a second before the figure cast a blindingly bright ball of white light. The aurors continued firing curses blindly into the room. The light dimmed significantly as the dementor glided forward, and went out entirely as the dementor entered the room and closed in on its prey.

"Expecto patronum", he said weakly. No patronus appeared and the dementor put its skeletal hands on his shoulders and pulled itself within inches of the man's face.

"Did Voldemort just try to cast a patronus?", someone asked.

"IT'S LOCKHART!", yelled Bahry, "EXPECTO PATRONUM!" His patronus pushed the dementor back.

Moody started to spin around when-

"Avada kedavra."

Moody dove to his left, spun in midair, and brought up his wand, "Avada-"

Lockhart (#1) was half-smiling as he activated his time-turner and disappeared.

"DAMMIT!" Moody yelled. He ran to the other room and pulled Lockhart to his feet, "You are going to give me some answers or I will rip them from your mind!"

"I had no choice. No choice. There's no choice. Never any choice. All a lie." Moody released him, and Lockhart collapsed into a sitting position, mumbling to himself.

"The dementor kissed him?"

Bahry shook his head, "I don't know. I was sure I stopped it in time. His dementor exposure should have been minimal."

Moody quickly checked Lockhart for polyjuice and possession. "You four, take him to St. Mungo's and keep him guarded. Have them check for metamorphmagus magic and see if they can figure out what's wrong with him. And get a legilimens in there to dig some information out of his head about what he's been doing. DAMMIT!"

Harry reached the end of the sink-tunnel and the beginning of a hallway. There was a table with a cauldron, glassware, and potions ingredients he recognized as those required for liquid luck. Luckily for him, the potion had clearly failed. The floor was littered with empty containers that he recognized as ingredients for polyjuice potion. Clearly Luna had directed him to the right place. He proceeded down the hallway.

Harry quickly took in the Chamber of Secrets. It was a relatively plain room other than for the massive statue. And the robed figure standing over what looked like a ten-foot long dead snake.

The figure turned to face him and drew back its hood, revealing a redheaded girl. "Oh, good, you got my message. We're long overdue for a real conversation. You have a certain reputation. We'll see if it's deserved. Let's start with something easy: have you deduced who I am?"

Harry just stared at Ginny for a moment in disbelief. She was holding a book with "Tom Marvolo Riddle" printed across the front in large letters. Finally he answered sarcastically, "Let me guess: something of a Riddle?"

Ginny hissed at him then angrily announced, "I am Lord Voldemort."

Harry chuckled, "I knew Voldemort, and you sir, are no Voldemort. Voldemort was one of the smartest people I've ever met. You may be above average by wizard standards of intelligence, but trust me, you're nothing special."

Ginny continued, "My name is actually an anagram of-"

"Marvolo isn't even your real middle name! I mean, it wasn't even the real Tom Riddle's real middle name. And why would you base your alter-ego on an anagram? Do you think anyone even cares about that? It's just dumb."

"If you use that muggle name again, you will regret it."

"Would you prefer Ginny Weasley?"

Ginny chuckled, "I've gotten quite skilled at playing that role. Though I'm mildly surprised you remember that name."

"I admit this is the first time I've seen Ginny do anything interesting."

Ginny chuckled again, "Fair point. On a somewhat related topic, what do you think about us collaborating on a project?"

"You recently killed several people. Including some who were useful and interesting. So you can understand that I'm not particularly inclined to help you with... what is it you want to do?"

Ginny smiled, "Become Minister of Magic and lead Wizarding Britain."

Harry shrugged, "Naturally. To quote my old defense professor, you are ambitious but you have no ambition."

"You think I'd tell you any plans of significance just because you asked?"

Harry shrugged and gestured at the snake, "You seem like the kind of person who would do something like that. Anyway, you're breeding basilisks. And using them to kill for you."

"Yes. That's all part of my master plan. Those students would have inevitably opposed me at critical times, so I had to eliminate them as soon as possible. I certainly didn't let the basilisk escape accidentally."

Harry's eyes widened for a second as he tried to calculate what level of deception that was, then replied, "That means you didn't just lose your temper and kill it. You intended to have a basilisk corpse over there because that's just your taste in interior decorating."

Ginny scowled at him, "Fine. I want the knowledge Slytherin's basilisk had. Creating my own basilisk was a small part of one possible plan for accomplishing that." Her expression lightened, "If you can contribute to that end, I will acknowledge your usefulness. Perhaps I'll even share some of the lost spells with you."

"Honestly, I am more than a little interested in getting those spells, but what exactly do you bring to the table in that arrangement?"

Ginny hissed, "I have far more experience with basilisks in general and Slytherin's basilisk specifically than anyone alive, including you, annoying child. I also have some memories of using some of the spells, so small hints may allow me to remember much more. What can you offer?"

Harry shrugged, "If you don't know, why are you asking for my help?"

Ginny looked angry for a moment, then smiled sweetly, "If you don't work with me, you'll never find Hermione."

"'Never' is a strong word. This place isn't that big."

"I don't think you're taking me seriously. Don't you realize who I am?"

"I'm not and I do. You're a first-year witch who has absorbed some memories from a seventh-year wizard who was an egomaniac and a wannabe dark lord. You think you're Voldemort, but you don't don't have his battle magic skills or experience, you don't have his knowledge of magic or his magical power, you don't have his followers, and you don't have his intelligence. The only important thing seventh year Tom Riddle had done is kill someone to make that diary. That doesn't make you a dark lord or an evil genius, just a thug with an ego."

"I think you're trying to anger me into making a mistake. Not a bad tactic, but clumsily executed. And obviously, I'm younger than the Voldemort this world knows, but I have the same potential. My future will be even greater because I will gain the same powers without repeating his mistakes."

"You have no future. Ginny will go home to her family and you will cease to exist."

She giggled, "There is no Ginny. I obliviated every one of her memories except for a few I needed to fool her family and friends."

"Yeah, that's the lie I'd tell in your place."

She cast a bat-bogey hex at him, then announced, "You're testing my patience."

Harry let his robe reflect the hex, "I'm a scientist. I test everything."

"So be it. Diffindo." She cast the curse not at Harry, but at the ceiling above him, cracking it and causing several large stone blocks to fall. "Jellyfy." As Harry was running out of the way of the falling rocks, he slipped and hit the ground, continuing to slide forward. "Avada kedarvra." Ginny dropped to a knee from the magical drain, while the green curse flew out on course to intercept Harry.

Harry accelerated, flying along the ground and the curse entered the floor behind him.

Meanwhile, Ginny called out, "Bassilissk, kill the intruder."

Harry ascended off of the floor, but landed awkwardly, "Bassilissk, go back to ssleep." He kept his gaze down, but heard something large moving behind the statue. He then fired a series of somniums in Ginny's direction.

She raised a prismatic sphere. "Silly child, an inferius only obeys its creator's commands."

The large something was getting closer. "Do the eyes of basilisk inferi kill? Or does that magic stop when they die?" Harry fumbled with his pouch.

"That's something else we can investigate together. I'll be the researcher, and you can be the test subject. I think I'm starting to see the appeal of this 'science' thing."

Harry activated the deluminator and the room plunged into darkness as every light went out. He quietly said, "That's another point for you, Dumbledore." He then ascended toward the ceiling, cast ventriliquo, and pointed his wand at the floor below him.

Ginny giggled, "Even if my basilisk can't see you, it can still hear you."

"Snakes can't hear, moron, they only feel vibrations." Harry tapped his glasses with his wand to activate his newest set of charms, then muttered, "crap", when nothing happened.

"Then how do they respond to parseltongue, you idiot?" She cast a series of glisseos, trying to either find Harry or help the basilisk locate him.

"That's just a magical linguistic interface, not a sense snakes can actually use." Harry slapped his palm to his forehead. He ripped a strip of cloth from his robes and tied it into blindfold. Once sufficiently separated from the room with the active deluminator, his glasses lit up. It had taken half the year and ultimately Flitwick's map-drawing spell, but Harry finally had a decent way to see in the dark: his glasses emitted ultrasonic pulses and used the return signals to draw a depth map.

Harry almost screamed. The basilisk inferius was about 20 meters long and its head was less than 3 meters away. It sniffed the air, turned slightly and sniffed again, clearly zeroing in on Harry. He dropped quickly and flew to the other side of the room. He decided to use Ginny as a human shield, and slowly flew a few circles around her to leave a scent trail.

She yelled, "I command you, sstrike now, sstupid ssnake!"

Harry watched the basilisk follow the path he'd flown, open its mouth and strike. The momentum drove Ginny's prismatic sphere backward into the wall. The snake backed up and prepared to strike again. Harry cast a shield-breaker which easily popped the overstressed shield, then cast a hover charm to rip the diary out of her hand and propel it onto one of the basilisk's fangs.

Ginny screamed and passed out. The basilisk fell to the ground, dead once again.